I remember the day I remember being at
我记得那天，我在家，
home and and getting the news and
听到这个消息，
laughing and crying and then it hits you
又哭又笑，然后突然意识到，
I was very
我非常非常难过。他（指吉米·帕特洛）真是太搞笑了，你们真是太棒了，
thank you very much thank
非常感谢你们！
[Applause]
[掌声]
you would you please welcome Jimmy one
请大家欢迎吉米，世界上
of the most respected and best love
最受尊敬、最受欢迎的
comedians in the world
喜剧演员之一，妙语
the king of on liners okay strap in
连珠之王。好了，大家系好安全带，
everyone you ready I'm going to start
准备好了吗？我要开始
teaching comedy because it teaches you
教喜剧了，因为它能教会你
how to come up with original thoughts to
如何产生原创的想法，
find your voice you'll be chasing
找到自己的声音。你会经历“
impostor syndrome and it's great you
冒名顶替综合症”，这很棒，你
should feel it every 18 months you
应该每隔18个月就体验一次。你会明白，
learned that failure is one of the great
失败是单口
gifts of standup comedy and to learn how
喜剧的一大馈赠，学会
to lose gracefully it's a good test of
优雅地接受失败是对你有多渴望的一个很好的考验。
how much you want something how do we
我们如何
know what we actually want I love what I
知道自己真正想要什么？我热爱我
do now but often question whether I
现在的工作，但我经常会问自己，我是否
should go be like a DJ D what I can
应该去做像DJ D那样的人？我可以
answer that question for you no you
回答你的问题，不，你不
shouldn't I know everything do you think
应该。我知道一切。你觉得，
oh maybe we can make a few quid out of
哦，也许我们可以靠
this no as a guy that's touring the
这个赚点钱？不，作为一个在世界各地巡演的人，我做不到。
world 300 days a year what advice would
一年300天，
you give me on how to be a better
你会给我什么建议来提升我的
Communicator speak at 92 beats a minute
沟通能力？我的演讲节奏是每分钟92拍。
when you look at the great public
你看那些优秀的公众
speakers they all seem to be hitting
演讲者，他们似乎都能达到
that rhythm of 92 beats a minute anxiety
每分钟92拍的节奏。焦虑
it's the flip side of creativity so I
是创造力的另一面，所以我
think the cure for managing my anxiety
认为克服焦虑的办法
is hang on the Netflix special drops
就是坚持下去。Netflix的特别节目
today so I imagine I'm being canceled
今天上线，我感觉自己
right now how have you come to deal with
现在好像要被“取消”了。你是怎么应对
that so the next time I get canceled
这种情况的？下次如果我被“取消”了，
I've got a plan here's what I'm going to
我已经有了计划。
do I'm going to say
我会说：“
congratulations diio gang we've made
恭喜各位，我们取得了
some progress 63% of you that listen to
一些进展。63%的听众
this podcast regularly don't subscribe
没有订阅我们的播客，
which is down from
比之前的
69% our goal is 50% so if you've ever
69%有所下降。我们的目标是50%！所以，如果你
liked any of the videos we've posted if
喜欢我们发布的视频，或者
you like this channel can you do me a
喜欢这个频道，能不能帮我个
quick favor and hit the Subscribe button
忙，点击订阅按钮？
it helps this channel more than you know
这对频道的帮助比你想象的要大得多。正如
you've seen the bigger the guest get
你所看到的，频道越壮大，我们邀请的嘉宾就越有分量。
thank you and enjoy this episode
谢谢大家，祝你们收听愉快！
[Music]
[音乐]
Jimmy it's great to be back what have
吉米 很高兴回来！
you been up to I've been you know I've
你最近在忙些什么呢？我最近一直在忙，到处走走，忙
been around I've been working I very
工作。上次来这里我很
much enjoyed this last time and I'm kind
开心，这次
of I was a bit nervous coming back
回来我还有点紧张，
because it's a Big Show and I I really
因为这是一场大型节目，我真的很
enjoy it I really enjoy listening so I
喜欢，很喜欢听大家的分享。所以我认真
I've given it quite a lot of thought
思考了很久，也
I've kind of made loads of notes and uh
做了很多笔记。嗯，我想先从这个开始：
I've been thinking a lot about gratitude
我一直在思考感恩，它是
as the mother of all virtues and I think
所有美德之母。我觉得
I'm right in saying this I think you
我这么说没错，如果
years time to be the age you are now and
你25年后还能保持现在的年龄和
as healthy as you are right now and I
健康状态，你愿意把所有财产都给我。我
think it's a really interesting
觉得这是一个很有意思的
meditation to think about right if you
思考题：如果你
had a time machine if you were 30 years
有一台时光机，如果你在30年后，
in the future if you could be this
如果你能保持现在的
healthy and feel this good and be this
健康状态，感觉这么好，
age you give everything materially that
年龄也这么大，你愿意把
you own in 30 years time to be back here
30年后所有物质财富都给我，只为回到这里。就先说到这里，
a minute just to take a moment to think
花点时间想想，
wow this is amazing what does that
哇，这真是太棒了！ 就当下的
Inspire in terms of Behavioral change in
行为改变而言，这会激发什么呢？
the moment well I think it's that thing
我觉得就像
of like I try and I think gratitude is
我尝试去体会一样，我认为感恩是一种非常
such an important virtue um and it's
重要的美德。
people talk about gratitude practice and
人们常说要练习感恩，这确实需要
it does take some practice and it often
一些练习，而且通常
takes like it's a it's like a way of
需要……它就像一种重新
reframing the way that you see the world
构建你看待世界方式的方法。
so I think that we suffer in the west a
所以我认为，在西方，我们多少都患有“
little bit from Life dysmorphia do you
生活畸形恐惧症”。你
hear a lot about body dysmorphia gender
经常听到“身体畸形恐惧症”、“性别畸形
dysmorphia we've got life dysmorphia a
恐惧症”吗？我们也有“生活畸形恐惧症”。
lot of people think their life is
很多人觉得自己的生活很
terrible because there's kind of the the
糟糕，因为就像陷入了某种
honic treadmill you get used to how
恶性循环，你习惯了
great your life is no one had a hot
自己生活的美好。
shower until 50 years ago so I Tred and
50年前，人们还没有热水澡。所以我尝试了一种
do this thing when you stand in a hot
方法，当你站在热水
shower George Mack my friend pointed
淋浴间时，我的朋友乔治·麦克指出了这一点。他说：“听着，当
this out to me went well look when you
你站在
stand in a hot shower just for a moment
热水淋浴间时，就一会儿，想想，
100 years ago had this simple pleasure
100年前你所敬佩的人，没有人享受过这种简单的
in life and when you look at the world
生活乐趣。当你看看
that we live in we we're like you're
我们生活的世界时，我们就像……” 你说的没错，历史上已经有
doing there been 100 billion people ever
1000亿人了，
right we are in the top top percentile
我们确实很幸运，处于极少数。
in terms of the luck that we have had
我们拥有如此优越的
the the lives like the the the calorific
生活条件，比如
intake that we just take for granted the
我们习以为常的卡路里摄入量，
fact that our children don't die uh you
我们的孩子不会
know in the first year the the modern
在出生第一年夭折，现代
medicine and our lives and our the
医学、我们的生活以及我们所
entertainment that we get we're living
享受的娱乐，都让我们感觉像
like kings and yet life has never been
国王一样生活。然而，客观来说，生活从未如此
objectively better and subjectively
美好，主观来说，生活却从未如此
worse
糟糕。这是
because the nature of humanity is our
因为人性的本质在于我们的
desires are memetic so we've got this
欲望具有模因性，所以我们很容易陷入一种怪圈：
happy are you well it's it's your
你有多幸福？其实，幸福的衡量标准是你的
quality of life minus Envy that's how
生活质量减去嫉妒。我们很
happy you are and it's easy to look at
容易去关注
everyone else and how they're doing and
别人过得怎么样，而忽略自己所
have it's funny because there's a cost
拥有的。这很讽刺，因为
to a hot shower isn't there and that's
洗个热水澡也是要付出代价的，不是吗？这正是
exactly what you're describing there
你所描述的。
because subjectively I think lot of
因为主观上，我认为很多
people don't feel like they are very
人并不觉得自己很
happy and I think objectively if you
幸福。而客观上，如果你
look at some of the stats around
看看关于
suicidality and depression and mental
自杀和抑郁症的统计数据，就会发现情况并非如此。 至于心理
health it doesn't appear that people are
健康方面，人们似乎并没有变得
any happier so even though we have sort
更快乐。即使我们在
of materially improved Our Lives we have
物质上改善了生活，比如
hot showers now there's a cost to the
现在可以洗热水澡了，但
hot shower in the sense that um maybe
热水澡也是有代价的。也许
it's made life too easy maybe it's made
它让生活太轻松了，也许它让
life too comfortable maybe we're in a
生活太舒适了，也许我们正处于
comfort crisis yeah I mean there's
舒适危机之中。是的，我的意思是，这有
there's a there's a lot to be said on
很多值得探讨的地方。
that I mean it's very I suppose it's
我的意思是，这或许是一种
very tough love but you can't have an
严厉的爱，但你不可能过上轻松的
easy life in a Great Character Show show
生活。伟大的人物剧集会告诉你，如果你看到一个
me a trust fund kid that inherited a
继承了一大笔钱的信托基金孩子，
bunch of money and I'll show you someone
我就会告诉你，他
mentally
内心饱受
tortured it's it's true right everyone's
折磨。这是真的，对吧？每个人都会说，
like your your struggle what where
你的奋斗历程是什么？
you've come from in Plymouth uh you know
你来自普利茅斯，你知道，曾经
in living in poverty to now having stuff
生活在贫困之中，而现在拥有东西
isn't fun getting stuff is fun right
并不快乐，获得东西本身才快乐，对吧？
it's not the pursuit happiness it's the
幸福不在于追求的过程，而在于
happiness of the pursuit right it's it's
追求的快乐，对吧？就是这样，
you know that the self-help it's not the
你知道，自助的意义不在于
journey it's the destination it's not
过程，而在于结果。 重要的不是
either the journey or the destination
旅程本身，也不是目的地，
it's who you become on the journey and
而是你在旅程中成为了怎样的人。
here's the terrible thing about life
人生最可怕的地方就在于
it's self-
它的自我
assignment like you know there's school
选择。你知道，你先上学，然后
and college and then you get dropped
大学毕业，之后
into the the real world at some point
某个时候你会突然被抛入现实世界，然后
and look and you go well you you have to
你会想，好吧，你必须
decide what you're going to do and you
决定自己要做什么。你
can take an easy path and it's it's
可以选择一条轻松的路，但这条路
ultimately less fun it's short money or
最终乐趣更少，收入也更低；或者你可以选择一条
you take a hard path and you give
艰难的路，给
yourself a challenge and it's great and
自己设定挑战，这很棒。
I think you know a lot of the times it's
很多时候，人们会说“这
that thing of like it's hard to do
很难做到”，这就是
that's a it's it's life is life is
生活，生活真的非常
really really tough those are tough
艰难，这些话
things to hear and it's it's easy for us
听起来很刺耳。对我们来说，这很容易，
because we're sort of on that road but
因为我们本身就在这条路上。但
then you know the thing I love about
你知道，我喜欢这个
this podcast is you're sort of trying to
播客的一点是，你试图用
there's so much kind of wisdom in it so
很多智慧和
many stories that you're sort of you're
故事，为
giving people this kind of road map for
人们提供一份路线图，告诉他们
okay well make your life a little bit
如何在短期内让自己的生活更
harder in the short term and and and get
艰难一些，最终到达某个地方。 我的
somewhere I mean I I didn't really get
意思是，我
what religion was until comparatively
直到人生比较晚的时候才真正理解宗教是什么，
late in life like the idea that God is a
比如上帝是
future right so so so God represents the
未来的代理人这种说法，对吧？所以上帝代表
future so work hard now for a better
未来，所以现在努力工作是为了
life in heaven right so that's it's kind
在天堂过上更好的生活，对吧？这其实和
of it's the same as all self-help like
所有自助书籍的理念都差不多，比如
sacrifice the present for the future
为了未来牺牲现在，
work is kind of the same it's a
工作也是如此，都是为了
better in the future that's like it's a
未来更好的生活而牺牲现在。这确实是一个
it's it's an interesting thing to sort
值得
of think around isn't it that like what
思考的问题，不是吗？想想
are you g to do now so I've got this um
你现在应该做什么？我和克里斯·
Chris Williamson you know Chris from
威廉姆森（Chris Williamson）聊过，克里斯是
he's a really good friend of mine he's
我的好朋友，他是个
lovely guy and we came up with this idea
很棒的人。我们一起想出了这个主意。
so me him and George Mack were chatting
我和他还有乔治·麦克（George Mack）在聊天，
about what what should you do today that
讨论你今天应该做什么，才能让你
you tomorrow would be happy you did so
明天感到高兴。也就是说，
sort of 24 hours in the future how best
在24小时后，怎样生活才是最好的。
to live because people sort of set like
因为人们常常会给自己设定一个目标，比如“
oh well I'm going to do something for 5
我要做某件事
years you know so it's this huge goal
五年”，你知道，这是一个巨大的目标，
but you won't rise to your goal
但你最终不会实现它，你会
you fall to your systems right so that
失败。 对你的系统来说，就是那种“
thing of like what could you do
你明天能做什么？
tomorrow what could you do today rather
你今天能做什么？”的想法，而不是让
that you'd be happy you did tomorrow
你明天做完之后感到高兴的事情，
whether it's the food you eat the
无论是你吃的食物、你做的
exercise you take the work you do what
运动、你做的工作，
do you do oh right I went to the gym
你都做了些什么？哦，对了，我昨天去了健身房，
yesterday I feel great like a a little
感觉很棒，就像有点
bit of Doms or oh I wrote 10 jokes and
Doms（一种印度甜点）一样。或者，哦，我写了10个笑话，
tonight I'm on stage trying those jokes
今晚我要上台表演这些笑话。
oh well I'm thanks me
哦，好吧，我感谢
yesterday I you know I did something
昨天的自己，你知道，我做了一些好事。
that was good so you can kind of time's
所以，无论
going to pass whatever you do and you
你做什么，时间都会流逝，你
can give yourself gifts in the future
可以给自己未来的礼物。
you can be rich and you can have a
你可以变得富有，你可以拥有
six-pack and you can be successful and
六块腹肌，你可以获得成功，
you can be in a happy long-term
你可以拥有幸福的长期
relationship with a beautiful family you
关系和美满的家庭。你
can give yourself those those gifts but
可以给自己这些礼物。但是，
present to give yourself that gift in
现在也有一些艰难的时刻，所以要给自己
the future something I really wanted to
未来的礼物。我真正
ask you about is you've climbed to the
想问你的是，你已经攀登到了
very peak of your profession like you
你职业生涯的巅峰，你
really are generational Talent this guy
真的是一代天才，没错，没错。
really you really have you think about
你真的应该想想你最初是从
where you started off at sort of 25
哪里开始的。
years old in your mid 20s when you
在你25岁，也就是20多岁的时候，你
decided to leave that I think
决定离开
advertising business and pursue comedy
广告行业，去追求喜剧事业。
like where you are now really is must be
你现在所取得的成就，对你来说一定是一个梦想成真，一个
the Dre a dream you like never really
你从未
imagined could come true you're at the
想过会实现的梦想。你正处于事业的
very peak of your profession and I think
巅峰。
at the peak of your profession I wonder
我想，在事业的巅峰，
sometimes if you wonder more than other
你有时会不会比那些仍在攀登高峰的人更频繁地思考这
that mountain what the point in all of
一切的意义？
this is well I think that's that's
我觉得这
incredibly interesting okay so there's a
非常有趣。好吧，这里有
couple of things to unpick there so you
几点需要分析。你
never feel like you're at the top of
永远不会觉得自己已经达到了
your profession because you're a you're
事业的顶峰，因为你
standing on the shoulders of giants in
站在你所在行业的巨人的肩膀上。
whatever industry you're in so you might
你可能会
think oh he's doing he's doing very well
想，哦，他做得很好，他很成功，
uh you know he's got a Netflix special
你知道，他有Netflix特辑，有
and a new tour and all of the you know
新的巡演等等。但你的内心却在想，嗯，
I write so the the thing that I try and
我写出的下一个笑话也好不到哪里去。所以我努力让自己保持
do is be quite stoic I'm trying to be
冷静，我努力让自己保持
I'm trying to do less better I'm trying
冷静。 少即是多，我只想
to just be a stand-up com the world
做个脱口秀演员。世界
ordered a standup comedian and I'm
需要脱口秀演员，我努力不辜负这份期望，对吧？这就是
people want right go out jokes tell
人们想要的，对吧？讲
jokes push the boundaries great that's
笑话，突破界限，太棒了！这就是
your little role in the world do that so
你在这个世界上的小小角色，去做吧！所以
the more I focus on that the the the
我越专注于此，效果就越好，
better it gets more people come to the
来看我表演的人就越多。就像
the whole of the world is built on
整个世界都是建立在
incentives right so you you you put down
激励机制之上的，对吧？你
sugar you get
吃糖，就会长蚂蚁；
ants you tell jokes you deliver on a
你讲笑话，在
show and people come and they enjoy it
演出中表现出色，人们来了，他们喜欢，
and then they come back next time what'd
下次还会再来。
you get out of that I mean the
你从中得到了什么？我是说
self-actualization I suppose the idea of
自我实现，我想就是那种“
going well I do this thing that I I very
我做这件事，我
much enjoy comedy because it's an
非常喜欢喜剧，因为它能
immediate feedback loop it's a it's a
立即获得反馈”的感觉。这是一个
very lucky business to be in because I
非常幸运的行业，因为我
don't have to wait like I don't have to
不用等待，不用
discuss with someone ah do you think
和别人讨论“你觉得
this joke's going to work or not what do
这个笑话行不行？
you think do you think it's too
你觉得它太
offensive or do you think ah tell it
冒犯了吗？”或者“你觉得……讲完
test it it's it's kind of it's the
试试看。” 这有点像
Silicon Valley the um you know uh the
硅谷，你知道，
the Dual testing is is this better than
双重测试就是，这个比这个好，这个比那个好，
this this or this I'm like an an ition
还是这个好？我就像个问题，
like just is this this or this or this
就像是，这个、这个、这个、这个、这个，这个措辞还是
or this this wording or this wording and
这个措辞更好？
the audience is a genius the audience
观众是天才，观众
tell me what works so it's it's kind of
告诉我什么有效，所以，这有点像，是的，
kind of to write a new show and then to
写一个新节目，然后把它
put something on the on the Shelf like
放到“架子”上，就像
the new Netflix special Natural Born
Netflix的新特辑《天生杀人
Killer now streaming on Netflix is is
狂》现在在Netflix上播放一样，
like it's it feels like I've given
感觉就像我给了
people irrefutable proof I am who I say
人们无可辩驳的证据，证明我就是我所说的那个人，
I am and that feels really good like
这种感觉真的很好，就像这就是
that's what I do that's better than the
我所做的，比上一个好。
last one and last time I was on the show
上次我上节目的时候，
I talked about wanting to write longer
我说过想写更长的
bits longer form like I I've got a great
段子，更长的形式，就像我有一个很棒的
fast ball but I haven't got a knuckle
快速球，但我没有指关节
ball and I wanted to try and write some
球，我想尝试写一些
different bits that maybe made some
不同的段子，也许能表达一些
points and I went away and I did it and
观点，然后我就回去写了，不管
for better for worse it's there and I I
好坏。 它就在那里，我试看了，
gave it a shot and I think it's a better
我觉得它
more rounded comedy special than the
比之前的喜剧特辑更好、更全面。
previous one and I and I don't hate the
我并不讨厌
previous one it's got really good jokes
之前的特辑，里面有很多很棒的笑话，真的很好笑，
in it it's really funny I like it and
我很喜欢。
then the new tour I think will be better
我觉得新的巡演会更好。
again I think you can see you see
我觉得你可以看到
progress and what are you chasing you're
进步，你不再追求什么了，
you're enjoying the process it's it's
你享受的是过程，是存在
being so I don't think you get
本身。所以，我不认为你会从健身房练
self-esteem from the six-pack you get at
出的六块腹肌中获得自尊，
the gym I think you get self-esteem from
我认为自尊来自于
being the kind of person that goes to
成为那种
the gym every day and I don't think you
每天都去健身房的人。我不认为你会从
having done the Netflix special but
Netflix特辑的演出中获得什么，但
being the person that put that together
作为策划者，这才是
is the that's that's the enjoyable thing
乐趣所在。你会在这方面有所
and you get you get kind of better at it
进步，
you you know the light the weight
你知道，重量
doesn't get lighter your back gets
不会减轻，你的背部会变得更
stronger I think about this with myself
强壮。我经常思考这个问题，
a lot I look at what I'm doing in
我会审视我在
business and stuff and with the podcast
商业上所做的一切等等。 做播客
and other things and I go there are
和其他事情的时候，
moments where my brain will ask myself
我的大脑会时不时地问自己：我的
the question like what's the end goal
最终目标是什么？
here because I've got the things that I
因为我已经拥有了
materially need need to be happy I could
物质上所需的一切，我本可以
retire and just go chill on a boat but
退休，然后去船上放松一下。但不知
for some reason I'm sort of torturing
为何，我在
myself in many respects but torturing
很多方面都在折磨自己，而且是那种
yourself very hard what you're doing
非常强烈的折磨。
you're giving yourself a character
你这样做是在塑造自己，
because you're giving yourself a
因为你在给自己设定
challenge right we all need the
挑战，对吧？我们都需要
challenge so it's like you know with any
挑战。就像任何
kind of mythological story it's the
神话故事里的
hero's journey and you're on a journey
英雄之旅一样，你踏上旅程，去
to to to do something to become
完成某件事，成为某个人，对吧？
are you doing here what's your role in
你在这里做什么？你在世界上扮演什么角色？
the world but going and sitting on a
但去海滩上坐着和
beach isn't anything like you there's a
你完全不一样。
reason holidays are are two weeks it's
假期之所以是两周是有原因的，
so you have three days of going ah we
这样你就有三天时间可以想：啊，我们该
should get back like holiday should be
回去了。假期应该是
10 days but somehow we we' made it two
十天，但我们不知怎么的就变成了
weeks and that's great because it allows
两周，这很棒，因为它让
people sort of three days of going you
人们有三天时间可以想：你
know what I've got to get back to work
知道吗？我得回去工作了。
I've got to do something I like that
我得做点什么，我喜欢那种感觉，就像站在
thing of like the top of your profession
你事业的顶峰一样。
well you'll always be looking ahead
你会一直向前看，看看
right at someone that's you know if it's
别人，比如，如果
for you probably Joe Rogan you go well
你的目标是乔·罗根，你会想，
Joe's got the biggest podcast in the
乔的播客是
world and what are you number two and
全世界最大的，那你排第二吗？
you and so you're you've got something
所以你有个目标。
to aim at and even if you're number one
即使你是第一，
then you're going to go yeah but radio
你也会想，是啊，但广播
still bigger so huh like that thing if
还是更火。所以，如果
you'll be chasing something giving
你一直在追逐某个目标，给
yourself maybe an artificial
自己设定一个未来可能人为的
um goal in the future but it's a it's a
目标，但这只是一个指引方向的指标。那么，
unhappiness involved in wanting to that
想要
thing off in the future you think you
在未来实现这个目标，是不是也包含了一些不快乐，某种自愿的不快乐呢？
know because if there's I sat with a
因为前几天我和一位
psychologist a psychiatrist the other
心理学家/精神科医生坐在一起，他也
day who was on the podcast and he said
上了我的播客。他说，
if you live your life continually
如果你总是
wanting you're essentially deferring
渴望得到什么，你实际上是在推迟
your happiness and replacing it with
你的幸福，并用当下的不满来代替它。我的
this is I mean listen even the worst
意思是，听我说。 即使是最糟糕的
people say great things chairman ma said
人也会说好话，马主席说过，
uh you can't smell the roses from a
你不可能在
galloping horse so when you're moving at
疾驰的马背上闻到玫瑰的芬芳，所以当你以
that kind of speed you don't take any
那种速度前进时，你根本没有
time to enjoy life right so you have to
时间享受生活，对吧？所以
just just enjoy the moment but you enjoy
你只能享受当下，享受
these conversations you enjoy the thing
这些对话，享受
that you do now the hard work is a lot
你现在所做的事情。现在，真正的挑战在于很多其他的
of the stuff around it you know the
事情，比如
travel and the the admin or whatever but
旅行、行政等等，但
you have to love the whole job you can't
你必须热爱整份工作，你不能只是
just go well I want that bit because in
想要那一部分，因为就像
the same way that people are jealous of
人们会嫉妒
you there'll be other podcasters that
你一样，也会有其他播客主播
are very jealous of what you've got but
非常嫉妒你所拥有的，但
they're jealous of what you've got
他们嫉妒的是你所拥有的，而
they're not jealous of how you got it no
不是你获得这一切的方式。没有哪个
comedians are jealous of how I got it no
喜剧演员会嫉妒我获得成功的方式，没有
one sits there and goes oh I wish I
人会坐在那里想，哦，我希望我
could sit for 10 hours a day and write
能每天坐10个小时写
jokes oh they think I'd want to play
段子，哦，他们会想，我想在
that venue or I'd love to have that
那个场地演出，或者我想拥有那个
Netflix special but they don't sit there
Netflix特辑，但他们不会坐在那里想，哦，
going well what pathology would you need
什么 你需要多么强的
in your head to write that many on
脑子才能写出那么多评论，才能如此
liners and to care that much about it
在意这些评论？
who would you have to be to do that and
你得是怎样的人才能做到这一点？
we're all chasing something right I
我们都在追逐着什么，对吧？我
think we're chasing impostor syndrome I
觉得我们都在追逐着冒名顶替综合症。我
think imposter syndrome's got a bad
觉得冒名顶替综合症
reputation and it's great you should
名声不好，但其实
feel it every 18
每隔18个
months as you level up you should feel
月，当你提升到一个新的层次时，你应该感受到这种感觉，你会想：
like do I belong here right this show is
我属于这里吗？这个节目比
much bigger than it was when I was last
我上次参加的时候规模大得多，
on congratulations you why is it bigger
恭喜你！为什么规模更大？
well because you pushed yourself and you
因为你鞭策了自己，更加
worked harder right and now sometimes
努力了。对吧？现在，有时候
you feel like oh my God I'm interviewing
你会觉得：天哪，我在采访
this
这个
person great don't feel comfortable
人，太棒了！别觉得舒服。
lovely as soon as you start to feel
亲爱的，一旦你开始觉得
comfortable you need to push yourself a
舒服，你就需要再加把劲。
my friend told me this a very Nam droppy
我朋友给我讲过一个很棒的
story you mind good all right Brandon
故事，一个非常……（原文拼写错误，无法准确翻译）……你介意吗？好的，布兰登·
Flowers told me this story so he's
弗劳尔斯给我讲了这个故事。
filming a video with Lou Reed like 10
大约十年前，他和卢·里德一起拍MV，
years ago they did a song with Lou Reed
他们为杀手乐队创作了一首歌，这首歌后来被翻译成其他歌曲。当时他们正在
backstage they're in the they're in the
后台拍摄MV。 他们在……
uh the The Green Room and Lou Reed's
呃，在绿屋里，卢·里德
there he's got leather trousers on he's
也在。他穿着皮裤、
got a leather jacket and a vest he's got
皮夹克和马甲，戴着
mirrored
反光
sunglasses he's Lou Reed and he looks in
太阳镜，他就是卢·里德。他看着
the mirror and Brandon sort of sees him
镜子，布兰登好像看到了他，就像在
just like checking himself out and Lou
打量自己。卢·
re just goes I wish I was that
里德心想：我真希望我是那
guy Lou Reed's got imposter syndrome and
个人。卢·里德得了冒名顶替综合症，但
he's Lou Reed there's nothing to matter
他可是卢·里德啊，这没什么大不了的。
with it you know a guy that's been a
你知道，一个
rock star and a legend for 40 years is
摇滚巨星，一个传奇人物，已经当了40年，
still feeling that thing of like going I
仍然会有那种“我觉得自己
don't feel like I'm that guy great
不是那个人”的感觉。太好了，
that's how you should feel so if you
你应该有这种感觉。所以，如果你
haven't felt imposter syndrome in the
在
last 12 18 months you think there's
过去的12到18个月里没有感受到冒名顶替综合症，你觉得
something probably what push yourself a
可能有什么原因，也许你需要
little bit hard I mean it depends it
稍微努力一下。我的意思是，这
depends what you want to do you can have
取决于你想做什么。你可以过
an easy life some people you know work
轻松的生活，有些人为了生活而工作，
to live some people live to work it's
有些人为了工作而生活。
it's there's different ways of doing
做事的方式有很多种，
things it's not necessarily you don't
你不一定非得……
that way like you're listening to us and
你就那样努力吧，就像你在听我们说话一样。
and you know there might be a
你知道，也许有个
psychiatrist listening going well these
精神科医生在听，他会说，这些
guys are pathologically ambitious this
人野心勃勃得病态，这
isn't healthy they should just be you
不健康，他们应该
know chilling out and maybe they have a
放松一下。也许他们说得
good
有道理。
point I look at your work ethic and I
我看了你的工作态度，
just feel like I've never seen anything
感觉我从未见过像你这样
like it for someone who is incredibly
如此
successful I look at your tour dates and
成功的人。我看了你的巡演日程，
I'm like this guy spends how many dates
心想，这家伙一年要演多少场？
a year on stage maybe 300 shows a year
大概300场吧，
something like that 300 shows a year
差不多300场。
well most people turn up to work every
大多数人每天都去上班，
day don't they I
不是吗？我的
mean you know it's also most people like
意思是，你知道，大多数人都是这样。
get get your average listener to the
你找个普通听众来听
show and go okay do you want to swap
节目，问问他们：你想不想交换一下
lives you you have to work for two hours
人生？你每天要工作两个小时，
a day but You' be telling jokes to
但你却在讲笑话，
people and it's joyful it's what what
而且很快乐。
looks like work to other people and
在别人看来是工作，但在
feels like play to you there you go
你看来却是玩乐。就是这样，这就是人们眼中
there's there say like as a really happy
真正幸福的
life that people go oh my God he worked
人生，人们会说：我的天哪，他工作
so hard and I'm going you're joking
这么努力，而我会说：你在开玩笑吧？
aren't you you are literally joking and
你简直是在开玩笑，
then you go oh the tour dates like this
然后你又说，哦，巡演日期，比如
last week I was in I know what South
上周我就在……我知道了，
Africa Paris Istanbul Budapest
南非、巴黎、伊斯坦布尔、布达佩斯、
Vienna what a life what because really
维也纳，真是精彩的人生啊！因为说真的，这就是
that's the other thing about life people
人生的另一面：人们
don't want to live longer they want more
不想活得更久，他们想要的是更多的
memories and and really how do you get
回忆。那么，怎样才能获得
more memories well it's it's doing novel
更多回忆呢？答案是：去做新鲜
interesting things so if you commute to
有趣的事情。如果你
work every day the same commute for a
每天都走同样的通勤路线，
year you don't have 300 memories of that
一年下来，你不会有300个关于这段
commute you've got one memory right but
通勤的回忆，你只有一个，对吧？但
if you do different things every day you
如果你每天都做不同的事情，
go to different places you talk to
去不同的地方，和
different people you you experience the
不同的人交谈，体验不同的人生，那该有多棒啊！
what that's a fantastic that Variety in
丰富多彩的
life gives you more memories more life
生活会给你带来很多乐趣。 记忆越多，生活越丰富。
you pointed at your head a second ago
你刚才指着自己的脑袋
and said we must be pathological in some
说，我们肯定在某些
way yeah do you think you are yeah yeah
方面有点病态。是啊，你觉得自己是吗？嗯，嗯，
I'm not sure I'm the I don't know I mean
我不确定，我不知道，我的意思是，我不确定，
I'm not sure I'm not entirely sure if
我不太确定
comedy isn't a uh some sort of low-level
喜剧是不是某种轻微的
Mental Health issue that you can turn
心理健康问题，你可以把它
into a career I it's you know it's like
变成职业。你知道，对
for most people it seems quite strange
大多数人来说，
to want to stand on stage and uh and
想站在舞台上讲
tell jokes I think it's it sounds
笑话似乎很奇怪，我觉得这对
terrifying to a lot of people but I find
很多人来说听起来很可怕，但我发现
it very very fun Have you ever figured
它非常非常有趣。你有没有想过
out why you are wide in such a way not
为什么你会这么宽容？没有，
really I mean I suppose that thing of it
我的意思是，我想这可以
goes back to Childhood it goes back to
追溯到童年，可以追溯到……
um my mother was an incredibly funny
我的母亲是一位非常幽默、性格开朗的
Larger than Life Irish woman I was very
爱尔兰女性，我和
very close to her I believe they call it
她非常非常亲近。我相信，
in meshed when you have like a very
当你
close relationship with your mother um
和母亲关系非常亲密时，人们会称之为“亲密关系”。
uh and she suffered with uh depression
她患有抑郁症，
and I didn't know you don't know as a
而我小时候并不知道，你知道，
kid your house is just your house you
你的家就是你的家。 我
think it's normal right so if your mom's
觉得这很正常，对吧？所以如果
in a dressing gown when you get home
你放学回家看到妈妈穿着睡袍，
from school and she hasn't got herself
还没收拾好，
together you just think well that's what
你就会想，嗯，
mom's are like so my whole childhood was
妈妈就是这样的。所以我的整个童年都是
aimed at making her laugh especially
为了逗她笑，尤其是在
driving fun thing to do make your mom
开车的时候。逗妈妈
laugh grab the steering wheel try and
笑的一个好方法是抓住方向盘试试。
you know have you had to unpack that to
你知道吗？你有没有想过，要不要把开车这件事从你的生活中剥离出来，让它不再影响
your adult life cuz I've thought about
你的成年生活？因为我
that a lot myself I think the things
自己也思考过很多次。我觉得，那些曾经
that have driven me here aren't
驱使我走到今天的事情，未必能
going to help me succeed in the next
帮助我在
phase of life whether it's being a
人生的下一个阶段取得成功，无论是像
father like I know you you know you've
我认识的你一样，在
2019 um or whether it's being in a
2019年生了孩子，还是
romantic relationship I've had to kind
谈恋爱。我必须
of really work hard to
努力去
unpack things so that I can succeed in a
理清思绪，才能在
new season listen I'm not a therapist
新阶段取得成功。听着，我不是心理咨询师，
but here's what I would say I think
但我想说的是，
you're going to have to make a
你需要
transition from looking at uh measurable
转变一下思路，不再只关注可量化的
metrics to immeasurable metrics I think
指标。 我认为，
you've got an amazing resume you've got
你拥有一份令人惊叹的简历，一份令人
an incredible CV of stuff you've done
难以置信的履历，上面记录着你做过的事情、取得的
and achievements and stuff you can point
成就等等，还有
the website and the money that you've
网站的浏览量、你赚的钱
made and the businesses You' started
以及你起步
great and I think the immeasurable stuff
很棒的企业。但我认为，那些无法衡量的东西将会
is going to become much more important
变得越来越重要。
so George Mack has this kind of theory
乔治·麦克有一个理论，认为
on we trade in life the measurable for
我们在生活中会用可衡量的东西去换取
the immeasurable so you trade work for I
不可衡量的东西。比如，你会用工作去换取陪伴父母的时间——我
know time with parents can't really
知道陪伴父母的时间是无法真正
measure time with parents and it's kind
衡量的。和父母一起吃顿
of it's tough to lunch with your parents
午饭很难，而
as opposed to the job and the thing and
工作、事情、
the work and that I'm busy I'm busy I'm
工作本身却总是让人觉得“我很忙，我很忙，我
busy and you only notice it when it goes
很忙”，只有当这些都消失的时候你才会意识到这一点。比如，
zero so mom dies and you go well I'll
妈妈去世了，你会想“我再也
never see her again what wouldn't you
见不到她了”，你会愿意
give now for another meal another time
付出什么来换取另一顿饭、另一次相处的时间、
another thing so you go trying to find
另一件事呢？所以你会努力
that balance in life and I think
在生活中找到平衡。我认为，为人
parenting and being a father is about
父母和为人父的意义就在
that isn't it it's about that
于此，不是吗？
it's about trading the the measurable
就是用可衡量的东西去换取不可衡量的东西。
for the immeasurable Warren Farrell
沃伦·法雷尔
tells a great story do you know Warren
讲故事讲得太棒了，你认识沃伦·
Farrell it's like the myth of male power
法雷尔吗？他就像是男性权力神话的化身。
I think a lot of his writing's been used
我觉得他的很多作品都被一些
by nefariously by people sort of that
别有用心的人利用了。
are a bit anyway he's a very interesting
总之，他是个非常有趣的
guy and he's he's very uh authentic um
人，而且非常真诚。
and he told this story I heard him tell
我听他讲过这样一个故事：一个非常
to me and very successful man you know
成功的人来找我，你知道，他是一家年收入数
millions really doing very well and he
百万美元的公司老板，事业非常成功。他
said he was unhappy because he had
说他很不开心，因为他一直在工作，错过了
worked all the way through his son's
儿子的整个
childhood and he didn't he hadn't bonded
童年，没有
with his son because he'd just been away
和儿子建立起亲密的联系，因为他总是忙于
work and he went went to see Warren
工作。于是他去找了沃伦·法雷尔，沃伦·法雷尔
farell and he's a you know psychiatrist
是一位精神科医生之类的。法雷尔
or whatever and he said uh okay what are
问他：“
you going to do he said well I'm going
你打算怎么办？”他说：“我打算
to I'm going to give up my job for 5
辞职五年，在家陪
my kid get I'm [__] it I'm not doing any
孩子。算了，我什么都不做了。” 在那
5 years just being that moment and he
五年里，我将陪伴我的孩子，就为了这一刻。他
did it and he was very happy that he did
做到了，他为此感到非常高兴。他
it it was John
是约翰·
lenon and no matter how important you
列侬。无论你
think your job is you're not John
认为你的工作多么重要，你都不是约翰·列侬。
lenon you know I'm sure he could have
我知道，我相信他本可以
done great things in those 5 years but
在那五年里成就一番伟业，但
you think oh my God I'm so glad he did
你会想，天哪，我真高兴他做了这件事，
that I'm so glad
我真高兴，
cuz of what an incredible artist he was
因为他是一位多么杰出的艺术家，
he'd given us so much and that he had
他给了我们那么多，他拥有了
those years for himself and that's for
属于自己的那几年。那是属于
him I mean I I imagine he's kid I
他的。我想他的孩子，我
imagine Shawn Lennon's very glad he did
想肖恩·列侬，一定非常高兴他做了这件事，
that but he got that
他拥有了那段
time and I imagine he didn't regret
时光，我想他不会后悔。
it and and his life was cut short
他的生命却不幸地戛然而止。
powerful when you consider that that he
当你想到他
didn't put it off he didn't go well I'll
没有拖延，没有想着“好吧，我先做这个，我先做那个，
do that I'll do I I'll get to I'll get
我先达到
to a million subscribers and then I'll
一百万订阅者，然后我再做
do that I'll sell a few more records and
那个，我再卖几张唱片，再
then one more tour and then I'll spend
巡演一次，然后……”时，你会觉得这一切更加震撼人心。 我会花
time with the family he he did it isn't
时间陪家人。他确实做到了。这不是
beautiful there's a lot of emotion in
很美吗？
your face when you tell that story it's
你讲这个故事的时候脸上有很多情绪，这真是个
beautiful story isn't it I mean I could
美丽的故事，不是吗？我的意思是，
when you think about it you go that's
当你仔细想想，你会觉得，这就是
kind of that's life isn't it and the and
人生，不是吗？至于
mortality I think is something we don't
死亡，我觉得我们
think about enough right I love that the
思考得不够多，对吧？我喜欢
Muslim uh uh phrase for death uh the
穆斯林对死亡的描述，那种
certainty
确定性。
you know we're in this brief shaft of
你知道，我们身处
Light Between Two Oceans of
两片黑暗海洋之间短暂的光芒之中。
Darkness everyone always thinks about
每个人都总是想着
happens after you die Mark Twain had
死后会发生什么，对吧？马克·吐温有
this great quote you know we we um he
一句很棒的名言，你知道，
said uh he said I wasn't alive for
他说，在
billions of years before my birth and it
我出生之前，我并没有活着数十亿年，但这
didn't inconvenience me in the
丝毫没有给我带来不便。
least but this brief shaft of Lights
但这短暂的光芒，真是太
kind of it's magnificent isn't it I
奇妙了，不是吗？我
think so I think it can
想是的，所以，我认为可以这样理解。
be this idea of um you know depression
你知道，抑郁症本质上就是过度
is essentially thinking about yourself
关注自己。
too much you last time we spoke on the
上次我们在
podcast you talked about I would say
播客里谈到这个，我会说，是的，
yeah sorry that that feels to me maybe a
抱歉，对我来说，也许……
little bit too harsh because I think
有点太苛刻了，因为我觉得
people suffer with depression and that's
人们会遭受抑郁症的折磨，这是
a it's a disease and it's incredibly
一种疾病，而且非常
serious and we think of suicide as being
严重。我们通常认为自杀是
something that stands alone it's not
孤立存在的，但其实不是，
it's a symptom of a disease called
它是抑郁症的一种症状。
depression right so it's the it's the
所以，自杀并不是
permanent solution to attemp problem you
解决问题的永久方案。你
don't want to feel this way anymore but
不想再感受这种感觉了，但
actually you don't want to feel nothing
实际上，你不想再有任何感觉了，
anymore uh you like to feel better so
你想感觉好一些。所以，
it's that thing of like I don't think we
我觉得我们对抑郁症的
talk about it enough but I think that
讨论还不够，但我认为，
yourself all the time I think just leads
总是想着自己，会导致
to a can lead to a Melancholy a sadness
忧郁和悲伤。
I think depression is maybe a slightly
我觉得抑郁症可能有点
separate thing not to nickp but it feels
特殊，我不是想贬低它，但感觉
like it feels like that's a disease yeah
它就像一种疾病。是的，
world MH and you're lucky if you're sad
世界上有很多悲伤，如果你感到悲伤，那你很幸运，
because if you're if you're sad it's
因为如果你感到悲伤，那通常是环境因素造成的，
circumstantial and you can do something
你可以做些什么来改变它。
about it you know are you depressed
你知道，你抑郁是
because you have serotonin imbalance in
因为你的大脑中血清素失衡吗？
your head and it's a heritable trait or
这是遗传特征，还是
are you sad because your life hasn't
因为生活不如意而感到难过？
out well if that's the case the latter
如果是后者，那
you're in luck because you can change
你很幸运，因为你可以改变现状。
the moment and I think your new show on
目前，年轻男性群体似乎正面临着一场危机，我认为你在Netflix上的新节目
Netflix shines a light on many of the
揭示了年轻男性
difficulties that young men are facing I
面临的诸多困境。
I was really excited to talk to about
我非常兴奋能和你探讨
this particular topic cuz I've been
这个话题，因为我
trying to arrive at a position myself on
自己也一直在思考，
why so many young men appear to be lost
为什么这么多年轻男性似乎迷失了方向，
and suicidality has increased and
自杀率也在上升。
there's you know these
你知道，现在出现了一些
new masculine influences or masculine
新的男性影响者，或者说男性
influencers that are really rounding up
偶像，他们正在影响着
this cohort of young men who who are we
这群年轻男性。我们
talking about and Tate Andrew Tates of
说的是谁呢？安德鲁·泰特，嗯，安德鲁·泰特这个人很
the world well Andrew T interesting
有意思，
isn't he because um who made the I think
不是吗？因为，嗯，
John meany made the observation Trump is
约翰·米尼说过，特朗普是
a poor person's idea of what a rich
穷人眼中的富人。是的，
person looks like yeah got gold Taps and
金·塔普斯，
I think s of Andrew Tate is like a
我认为安德鲁·泰特就像一个
14-year-old boy's idea of what
14岁男孩的…… 人们对男子气概的理解其实很肤浅，当然，
nature abor a vacuum and there's a real
自然界本身就是一个真空，而
vacuum for um Elders like we now we
长辈们在这方面确实存在着很大的空白。比如我们现在
don't learn how to shave from our
不会从父亲那里学习如何刮胡子，而是通过
fathers it's a YouTube video and so you
YouTube视频。因此，我们在
lose something in that in that bonding
这种传承中失去了一些东西。
so there's a big bit in the new show
所以在新节目里，有一段
where I give a young guy an audience
我“刁难”了一位年轻的
member a pretty tough time like we have
观众，我们进行了一番
the talk and I give them advice on how
谈话，我给他提了一些关于
to uh be with a woman and it's I'm not
如何与女性相处的建议。我说的
wrong about anything it's really funny
没错，这真的很有趣，也
and it's really rude but I'm not wrong
很粗鲁，但我说的都是对的。
about stuff it's like it's about consent
这涉及到“同意”的问题。
and it's it's I think it's really it's
我认为这真的
really good because it's I've sugared
很好，因为我用一种比较委婉的方式来表达
the pill of the message because people
这个信息，因为人们
don't want to talk about it people go
不想谈论它。人们会说“
it's obvious what consent is yeah not to
同意”是什么显而易见，但对
17-year-old boys or girls it's like
17岁的男孩女孩来说并非如此。
actually what what does that look like
实际上，同意到底是什么？它
and how should that be so it's uh yeah
应该是什么样的？所以…… 嗯，是的，这套
it's a it's a really fun routine really
流程真的很有趣，
fun routine to perform and to write what
表演和创作都很有趣。
is it to be a man these days cuz it's
如今做男人到底意味着什么？因为即使是关于
conversation around like chivalry and
骑士精神和
understanding you know well people talk
理解的讨论也让人很困惑。你知道，人们谈论
about toxic masculinity and easy fix be
有毒的男子气概，而最简单的解决方法就是做
a gentleman be a
一个绅士，做一个真正的男人，就是这样。
gentleman is never rude by
绅士永远不会无意中粗鲁无礼，
accident it's Christopher Hitchin line
这是克里斯托弗·希钦的名言。
great I I don't know I mean my thing
我不知道，我的意思是，
about young men today if I was going to
如果我
give young men advice it would be
要给现在的年轻人一些建议，那就是
get the right drugs and the real thing
找到合适的“毒品”，
right in real life live in real life
在现实生活中体验真正的生活。那么，
right so why young men are obsessed by
为什么年轻人会沉迷于
video games right obsessed they're
电子游戏呢？他们沉迷于此，花费
spending hours and hours and hours
数小时
online playing video games why well
在线玩电子游戏。为什么呢？因为电子游戏
that's a proxy for career right video
是他们职业生涯的替代品。
games you think about the levels of
想想
video games and what people do on video
电子游戏的关卡，想想人们在游戏中做的事情，这就像一个
games it's that's a proxy that's like a
替代品，一个
career that they're not having and then
他们没有从事的职业的替代品。
they spend a lot of time you know
他们花很多时间对着
fapping to to Pornhub or uPorn or
Pornhub、uPorn之
whatever and that's a proxy for sex and
类的网站撸管，这其实是性的一种替代。
my thing would be George Orwell wasn't
我的观点是，乔治·奥威尔说的
right our power won't be taken away from
不对，我们的权力不会被
us by some authoritarian master we're
某个独裁者夺走，我们会
going to give it away for cheap dopamine
为了廉价的多巴胺而放弃它。而
and the cheap dopamine of video games
电子游戏、
and online porn and living online is is
网络色情和网络生活带来的廉价多巴胺正在
is getting in the way of real life so
妨碍现实生活，所以
it's risk
这很冒险，对吧？这就是
right that's that's what we're not
我们
allowing young people to do because we
不让年轻人做的事情，因为我们
we're saying to young people you can't
告诉年轻人，你不能
take risks in real life we're we're
在现实生活中冒险。我们是在“
helicopter parenting we're not giving
直升机式育儿”，我们没有给
them the freedom how much Freedom should
他们自由。那么，应该给孩子多少自由呢？应该
you give a kid as much as they can cope
给他们能够承受的自由。14
with right 14year olds used to be
岁的孩子以前是
babysitters they now need
保姆，现在他们需要
babysitters that's not good right so you
保姆，这不好，对吧？所以，你
should allow them more freedom in in the
应该在现实世界中给他们更多的自由，
real world because otherwise the only
否则
place they get freedom is
他们唯一能获得自由的地方就是
online and no freedom in the real world
网络，现实世界里没有自由。
you're not allowed to go to the park and
你不能去公园
hang out but you're allowed to do
闲逛，但你可以做
whatever you want online well that's a
任何你想做的事情。 在网上，这
that feels like a very bad social
感觉就像一个非常糟糕的社会
experiment that feels like a bad
实验，感觉像个糟糕的
idea yeah it feels like we've
想法。是的，感觉我们
inverted um Ma you know masloff this P
颠倒了马斯洛夫的
pyramid hierarchy of needs and you go
需求层次理论（P金字塔）。你知道，
well food and shelter and warmth and all
食物、住所、温暖等等，
worked out in our society right we we
我们社会已经解决了所有底层的需求，对吧？我们却
kind of can't see it we're not grateful
看不到，我们对此并不感激，
for that because we can't see the hot
因为我们看不到热水
shower the Hot Shot we can't see the
澡，看不到热水淋浴，看不到
third world and we can't see the people
第三世界，看不到
in the past having a tougher time than
过去的人们比
us so we take it for granted but we
我们过得更艰难，所以我们把这一切都视为理所当然。但我们
worked out that stuff they hadn't worked
解决了这些问题，
that stuff out 200 years ago but they
200年前的人们并没有解决这些问题，但他们已经理顺了
had the top of the pyramid sorted
金字塔的顶端，
everyone knew who they were they had
每个人都知道自己是谁，有
their identity and they knew what their
自己的身份，知道自己的
purpose was everyone knew who they were
目标是什么，每个人都知道自己是谁，知道自己的意义，
what they were about and they were
他们与
group and now we're kind of free
群体中的其他人联系在一起。而现在，我们就像
floating individuals we kind of worship
漂浮的个体，我们崇拜
the individual as if as if we can
个体，仿佛我们可以
survive as
作为
individuals I always think of that thing
个体生存下去。我总是想到，就像
of like there's no such thing as a
没有
baby there's a baby in a mother there's
婴儿这种东西一样…… 母亲体内有婴儿，有
a baby and a father baby and an auntie
婴儿和父亲，有婴儿和阿姨，
but there's no such thing as a baby
但婴儿本身并不存在，
because a baby on its own isn't anything
因为婴儿本身什么都不是，
it's it's dead it's you it needs taken
它已经死了，它是你，它需要被
care of we're all still babies we all
照顾。我们都还是婴儿，我们都
need the
需要与他人建立
connections you you yourself yeah sure
联系。是的，当然，你有
there's there's a lot of yourself that's
很多
that's within you but a lot of it is out
内在的东西，但很多东西都存在于外部
in the world it's connected to other
世界，与其他人相连，它在某种程度上
people and it kind of it mediates who
调节着你对自我的认知。
you think you are and that's you know
你知道，这正是当今社会所
that's that's slightly missing from
缺失的，在当今
society where you kind of live online
社会，人们生活在网络世界里，
and you're kind of a self-authored thing
你仿佛成了一个自我塑造的存在，
you're just on on the computer on the
你只是待在电脑
screen and you're not connected and
屏幕上，你与他人隔绝，
you're not taking risks taking risks is
你不去冒险。冒险
really
真的很
important is this in part due to the
重要。这部分原因是否与
rise in atheism and agnosticism I think
无神论和不可知论的兴起有关？我想
we we both me and you lost our sort of
我们俩，我和你，都在差不多的
religious Faith around the same age
年纪失去了宗教信仰，大概在20岁左右。
think sort of early mid mid mid2 I think
我觉得
it's a weird thing where you go you can
这很奇怪，你会
lose your I I certainly don't believe in
失去你的……我当然不会。 相信
the stories there's two types of fools
这些故事，有两种傻瓜，对吧？一种是
right there's people that take religion
把宗教
literally and there's people that think
当真，另一种是认为宗教
it has no
毫无价值。
value okay both both idiots for
好吧，这两种傻瓜都是傻瓜，只是
different reasons like it works as a
原因不同。
thing religion I quite I miss it because
宗教作为一种东西确实有效，我挺怀念它的，因为
the reason the ceremony Works isn't
仪式之所以有效，不是
because God's pleased it's because the
因为上帝高兴，而是因为
people came together and so I think we
人们聚集在一起。所以我认为我们
look for things that that are um proxies
寻找的是
for religion and sometimes that's could
宗教的替代品，有时可能是
football it could be Environ ISM you
足球，也可能是环保主义。你
know because you go well I need
知道，因为你会想，我需要一些东西，
something I need purpose in my life I
我需要人生的意义，我
need to feel like I'm I'm adding value
需要感觉自己在创造价值，多么
and what a great cause I'm going to save
伟大的事业啊，我要拯救
the planet it's a big thing to think
地球！这的确是一件大事，它带有
about it's got a religiosity to it but I
宗教色彩，但
don't think that's the you know I don't
我认为这并非
think that's necessarily the answer you
答案。
know some people do it with politics
有些人把这种想法寄托在政治上，
they think politics is going to is going
他们认为政治就是
to be Heaven they're going to they're
天堂，他们会找到
going to come up with some perfect
某种完美的
system I think you're putting too much
体系。我认为你
pressure on politics first time I've
对政治施加了太多的压力。这是我第一次…… 我
ever said this actually but when you
其实没说过这话，但你
just said I I think Miss religion I
刚才说我想念宗教，我想念
think I miss religion it's nice wasn't
宗教，这感觉真好，不是吗？
it it's a lovely thought as well when
当
you lose someone that you love very much
你失去挚爱之人时，这感觉也很美好。
it's a lovely thought I mean Heaven is
我的意思是，天堂……这感觉很
just it's a lovely thought and I think
美好。我觉得
in a way in our culture Fame and Fortune
在某种程度上，在我们的文化中，名利
has replaced
已经取代了
Heaven it's the land of milk and honey
天堂。天堂是充满牛奶和蜂蜜的地方，在那里
and where you can feel like you're um uh
你会觉得
everything's okay everything's taken
一切都很好，一切都有人
care of um and it is
照顾，这当然
good but it's it's not it's not heaven I
很好，但它不是天堂。我
don't believe in an afterlife I believe
不相信有来世，但我相信有来生。
life so I don't think anything happens
所以我不认为死后会发生什么，
after you die but I think you can have a
但我认为你可以有来生，一个
next life a very different life so it's
截然不同的来生。所以很
interesting you're at this point of your
有意思的是，当你到了人生的这个阶段，
your life when you're thinking about
当你考虑
well we might start a family it's a
组建家庭时，那将是一个完全不同的人生，一个完全不同的
whole other life it's a whole other
人生。
you'll hardly recognize yourself you and
你几乎认不出自己了。你和
your partner will be saying what did we
你的伴侣会整天说“我们今天都干了些什么”，
do what did we do all day now we're not
我们不再是《
a Peppa Pig World or wherever you find
小猪佩奇》的世界，或者其他什么地方了。
yourselves it's really just struck me
说真的，我突然意识到
that I do kind of Miss religion but it
我确实有点想念宗教，但
feels like when I lost my religion I put
感觉就像失去信仰后，我背上了
a backpack on a backpack full of weights
一个装满重物的背包。
on and I think that's what the
我想这就是
responsibility and individualism is I
责任和个人主义的意义所在。
mean for me the the loss of religion was
对我来说，失去宗教就像
A Rush of Blood to the Head it was like
一股热血沸腾的冲动，就像是“
oh I I this is my life and I need to
哦，这是我的人生，我必须
make good on this and I need to live it
好好把握，我必须活出精彩”。
the tragedy is most people don't have
悲剧的是，大多数人没有这种经历，
that kind of they don't get to kind of
他们无法
follow their their their dream when you
追逐自己的梦想。在你
were 28 years old your mother died who
28岁的时候，你的母亲去世了，她对
you for many reasons but also has very
你的影响非常深远，原因有很多，但她也是你
career when I read through your story
事业的灵感来源，或者至少是你事业发展的最大推动因素。我读过你的故事，
even more recently you've undergone
最近你经历了
quite a lot of grief even the loss of
很多悲痛，甚至包括失去
your dog I believe um which had a pretty
你的爱犬，我相信这
large impact on you I think grief is
对你打击很大。我认为悲伤是
cumulative so every time you lose
累积的，所以每次失去
someone or something uh and and actually
某人或某物，都会带来新的感受。
losing a pet can be it's a weird thing
失去宠物其实很特别，
because people lose pets and it's like I
因为人们失去宠物…… 感觉就像我
don't know the other people in the
不知道办公室里的其他人
office can be about H okay oh well what
会怎么想，比如“好吧，
we doing for lunch it's like can be a
我们午饭吃什么？”之类的。这可能真的会让人很受触动，
really affecting thing because it's not
因为这
just just everyone you've lost and you
不仅仅是关于你失去的所有人，你会
think about mortality but you think
思考死亡，你也会思考
about your own mortality and you think
你自己的死亡，你会思考，你
about you know you kind of think about
知道，你会思考，
it takes you to a very melancholy place
这会把你带到一个非常忧郁的地方，就像
of like at some point you got to say
在某个时刻你必须说
goodbye and I guess you think about
再见。我想你会思考
those things of going what are the you
这些事情，比如，你
know in life as we were talking about
知道，在生活中，就像我们刚才谈到的，
the the the great you can have great a
你可以有一份很棒的
great resume great CV loads of stuff on
简历，一份很棒的履历，上面有很多东西，
it but what are people going to say at
但是人们会在
your eulogy that's the important thing
你的悼词上说什么？这才是重要的，
that's the stuff that really matters
这才是真正重要的东西。这
and it's a very different it's again
非常不同，这又
it's the it's the it's a hidden metric
是一个隐藏的衡量标准，衡量
of what people going to say at your your
人们会在你的
funeral what what are people going to
葬礼上说什么，衡量人们在
say when you when you
你
pass uh I don't know I think grief's
去世时会说什么。嗯，我不知道，我认为悲伤，这
it's a it's very interesting it's very
很有趣，非常……
it is that thing of it you know kind of
你知道，这种感觉就像
comes in waves and you think about it
潮水一样一波接一波地涌来，你会想
for a long time and then it and then it
很久，然后突然就
hits you how have you dealt with grief
涌上心头。你以前是怎么应对悲伤的？我的
life I mean I I I think when my uh I
意思是，我觉得，嗯，我
don't know I think I think I'm slightly
不知道，我觉得我有点
guilty of you know suppressing it a
压抑自己的悲伤。
little bit I think when uh I think when
我觉得，
Shawn lock died I was very
肖恩·洛克去世的时候，我非常非常
uh very upset by it and you just go to
难过，然后你就去
work you just kind of go well I'll I'll
上班，你会想，好吧，我让
put myself in this joyful place of
自己沉浸在快乐的
laughter and maybe not have to think
笑声中，也许不用
about it as much but it's
想那么多。但是，
uh yeah it's you know they gone forever
嗯，你知道，他们永远地离开了。
about when sha died because people
肖恩去世的时候，发生了一件很特别的事情，因为人们在
shared so much online so you had
网上分享了很多，比如，
these clips of like I remember the day I
我记得那天我在家，
remember being at home and and getting
听到
the news and laughing and crying kind of
消息的时候，又哭又笑，那种
real kind of um cognitive dissonance of
认知失调的感觉很真实，
like feeling really upset and then they
感觉非常难过，然后他们
played just all the funniest clips of
播放了肖恩所有最搞笑的片段，
Sean like people just sending me clips
人们不停地给我发
clips clips and he was just so funny and
片段，他真的太有趣了，而
that Joy is kind of there it's it's it's
快乐是善良的。
of social media ills on that day my God
那天社交媒体上充斥着各种弊端，我的天啊，这真的改变了一切。肖恩
passed I I don't know whether there's
去世后，你对肖恩和人生有了哪些新的感悟？我不知道这其中是否蕴含着
any great Revelation in it I think it's
什么伟大的启示，但我认为就是要懂得
that thing of just you know enjoy you
享受，享受你
know enjoy your time enjoy the enjoy
的时光，享受
this because it's fleeting I mean all
这一切，因为生命转瞬即逝，对
too fleeting for for Sean who's very
肖恩来说，生命太短暂了，他那么
young uh but it's you know I think that
年轻。但我觉得，
you know family and and you know
家庭，和爱的
spending time with the people that you
人在一起，
love and and doing what you love I think
做自己喜欢的事，这些才是最
prioritizing that it's if you want to
重要的。如果你想
meet someone high agency meet someone
认识一个有主见的人，那就去认识一个只剩
that's got six months to live I'd say
六个月生命的人，我想说，
their tolerance for [__] is is about
他们对胡说八道的容忍度大概是
as low as it
最低的。
gets I think living your life like that
我觉得这样生活
is not a bad idea if really shows you
并不坏，它真的能让你明白
what your priorities would be someone
你的优先事项是什么。如果有人告诉你
said you had six months to live well
只剩六个月的生命，你会
do that's how what you should be doing
做什么？这就是你应该做的。
anyway yeah that's really what I'm what
是的，这就是我真正想说的。
I'm getting at is there's something that
我想说的是，
facing our own mortality teaches us um
直面死亡会教会我们一些东西，
but unfortunately we have to we often
但不幸的是，我们常常是在
learn that when we we haven't got a lot
没有太多
of time to implement it and sometimes
时间去实践的时候才意识到这一点。有时，当身边亲近的
when we when someone close to us passes
人
away we can vicariously learn that
离世时，我们才能间接地领悟到
message about our immortality and what
关于永生、关于人生
really what our priority should be and
真正优先事项、关于我们应该如何
really how we should be living our life
生活、关于什么才是
and really What mattered the most and I
最重要的。我
imagine losing someone that was as close
想，失去像莎这样亲近的人，会让我们明白
to you as Sha was sends you some kind of
一些
message about priorities and life and
关于优先事项、关于生命、关于
gratitude and all these things we talked
感恩以及我们之前讨论过的所有这些事情。是的，
yeah I think it's yeah I think gr
我认为
gratitude's a big part of it as well
感恩也是其中很重要的一部分。
that idea of kind of going wow that was
那种感觉就像是，哇，这
that was pretty
太
special you you were I might grab I
特别了，你……我可能……我
might grab another coffee can I grab the
可能再去拿杯咖啡，我可以把
rest of my coffee yeah yeah is that all
剩下的咖啡拿走吗？可以，
right am I allowed yeah he said breaking
可以吗？ 打破
with format I might shuffle my notes as
常规，我可能也会重新整理一下笔记。
well I'm going to shuffle my notes
我打算重新整理一下笔记。
this is a business podcast or at least
这是一个商业播客，或者至少它最初是这样
that's how it started and is it have You
开始的。你
Have you listened back because I don't
有没有回听过之前的节目？因为说实话，我
think it is I'll be honest with you it's
觉得它
it's not this is but business is life
不是。但商业就是生活，
you know what I mean and they're the
你知道我的意思吗？它们本质上是
same thing the communication mental
一样的：沟通、心理
health striving progress people
健康、奋斗、进步、
relationships it's all business at the
人际关系，归根结底都是商业。我的
end of the day it I mean you are re I
意思是，你……我的意思是，
mean this I mean I know it's still cool
我知道《
diary the CEO but re I don't think
CEO日记》仍然很酷，但……我想
you've talked about business on this for
你已经三年没在这个播客里谈论商业了，
like 3 years and even then it was like a
即使是以前，也只是偶尔提及。
passing so when you started your
所以，当你开始
business how did that make you feel it's
创业的时候，你感觉如何？
this isn't you're an old hippie is what
这不是说你是个老嬉皮士。
you are you love this is a great podcast
我喜欢这个播客，
but this is a storytelling podcast so
但它是一个讲故事的播客。
many of so many entrepreneurs are old
很多企业家都是老
hippies I think of Steve Jobs he was an
嬉皮士，我想到史蒂夫·乔布斯，他就是个
Old Hippie yeah you know and it's
老嬉皮士。是的，你知道，这很
interesting I think that thing of like
有意思。我觉得，
uh what does business teach people like
商业能教会人们什么呢？ 就像
we're talking about like young men and
我们谈论年轻男性一样，现在
going on out there uh with young men and
年轻男性群体正面临着一些危机，
and young women are not having an easy
年轻女性的处境也不容乐观，但年轻男性的
the the suicide rate whatever um is
自杀率等等问题尤其严重，令人震惊。
horrific with young men and you go well
你会想，到底发生了什么？问题在于自主性。
what's going on and it's agency I don't
我
think we're giving young people enough
认为我们没有给予年轻人足够的
agency so they don't feel like they have
自主权，让他们感觉自己没有
they have control and really I think the
掌控权。实际上，我认为像
thing of like serial entrepreneurs like
连续创业者那样的人，似乎
no one ever seems to hit on their first
没有人能一蹴而就地创办第一家
company but it's the second and third
公司，而是第二家、第三家、
and fourth and but they just keep going
第四家，他们不断尝试，心想“
they go well I'm never going to work for
我永远不会为
anyone I'm going to do it myself that's
任何人工作，我要自己创业”。我
kind of I don't think we're teaching
认为我们没有在这方面给予
enough of that uh it's it's a weird
足够的重视。这很奇怪，因为
thing CU like teaching someone to be a
教人如何
self-starter is kind of a contradiction
自主创业本身就有点自相矛盾，
in terms but it's it it kind of works
但实际上却行得通。
right there's I think we're teaching the
我认为我们教
wrong things I've Got a Theory I think
错了东西。我有一个理论，我想
I'm going to start teaching
我会…… 开始教
comedy and and okay so comedy is very
喜剧吧，好吧，喜剧其实很
new it really you could trace its roots
新，它的根源可以
back to George Carlin and Richard PRI in
追溯到70年代初的乔治·卡林和理查德·普里，
the early 70s as like one guy on stage
就像一个家伙
in a big theater and he's selling
在一个大剧院的舞台上表演，
tickets and people are just seeing him
卖票，人们只是来看他，对吧？
right you can trace it back to the dawn
你可以追溯到
of time but really the modern standup
远古时代，但现代单口喜剧的
early '70s is a good good starting point
起点其实是70年代初。
right so it's a very new medium compared
所以，与音乐和电影相比，它是一种非常新的媒介，对吧？
to music and film right it's very new so
它真的很新。所以
I sort of view George Carlin and uh
我把乔治·卡林和
Richard PR they're John the Baptist
理查德·普里比作施洗约翰，
right and and Jesus isn't here yet and
耶稣还没来呢。
it's this new evolving medium and unlike
它是一种不断发展的新兴媒介，不像
music we don't have a language yet so we
音乐，我们还没有一套语言。所以我们
need a language of like okay what are
需要一套语言，比如，什么是
the joke types and how could you how do
笑话类型？如何
you how do you write that down how do
写出来？如何
you configure it there's too much
组织它们？
magical thinking around stand-up comedy
关于单口喜剧，有太多不切实际的幻想，
you know the idea that I I just I just
你知道，我刚才
came up with it it's just yeah I just
说的那些想法，其实只是……嗯，我只是……
but actually learning how jokes work and
但实际上，学习笑话的运作方式，
uh systematizing and uh analyzing them I
系统化地分析它们，我
think really helps so I've been working
认为这真的很有帮助。 所以我一直在
on a book with um uh Amanda Baker who
和阿曼达·贝克（Amanda Baker）合作写一本书，她之前
helped me on my first book uh we've been
帮我写过第一本书。过去几年我们一直在
working on a thing together for the last
合作，
couple of years trying to teach comedy
尝试教授喜剧。
and I think I think there's a real
我觉得这真的
benefit to it because if you think about
很有意义，因为想想
music in schools right we'd all argue
学校里的音乐课，我们都会说
learning music's great right it's great
学习音乐很棒，对吧？
idea teach kid the piano grade three
教孩子钢琴三年级，让他们
learn something about music and they'll
了解一些音乐知识，他们以后会
appreciate music much more in life I
更欣赏音乐。但我
think comedy is much more relevant right
认为喜剧更有意义，对吧？
what does comedy teach you right it
喜剧能教你什么呢？它能
teaches you you would you learn to kind
教你如何
of you find your self and you find your
找到自我，找到自己的
voice and you learn to communicate your
声音，学会表达自己的想法，如何整理
ideas and to order them and write them
思路，如何写
down and uh to communicate it's very
下来。沟通非常
valuable like the great tragedy of life
重要，因为人生最大的悲剧
is most people live and die and never
就是大多数人活着，死去，却从未听过
hear their own
自己的
voice everybody wants to be a better
声音。每个人都想成为更好的
speaker a better Communicator you know
演说家，更好的沟通者。你知道吗，这很
it's funny cuz I sat with a guy called
有趣，因为我之前和一位叫朱利安·
um Julian treasure who has I think Ted
特雷泽（Julian Treasure）的人坐在一起，他有一个关于
Talk on communication and speaking that
沟通和演讲的TED演讲，点击量大概有
did I don't know 30 40 million views and
三四千万。
he said I also did a Ted Talk on
他说我还做过一个关于倾听的TED演讲，呃，难道
listening ick can no one listen to it
没人听过吗？
everyone listen to the talk about being
大家都去听听那个关于如何成为
a better
更好
speaker that's that's that's pretty
演讲者的演讲吧，这真是太
funny uh the uh yeah know I could
搞笑了。嗯，是的，我知道，我能
imagine that you as a as a guy that's
想象你作为一个
touring the world 300 days a year you
一年300天都在世界各地巡回演讲的人，
must have really been able to break down
一定非常了解
the science of communication and being a
沟通的科学原理，以及如何成为一名
good speaker that's transferable to
优秀的演讲者，这些原理可以应用到
business public speaking life sales
商业、公众演讲、生活、销售
Etc what would what advice would you
等等领域。你
give me on how to be a better speaker
会给我什么建议，让我成为一个更好的演讲者/
Communicator all right
沟通者呢？
okay 92 beats a
好的，每分钟92拍，这是什么
minute what does that mean speak at 92
意思？以每分钟92
beats a minute that's there you go I
拍的节奏说话，就是这样。我的
mean there's kind of a science behind it
意思是，这背后是有科学依据的，
and I've looked into it but most great
我也研究过。大多数优秀的
public speakers sort of speak in a
公众演讲者说话都有
rhythm but it doesn't matter how fast
节奏感，语速快慢并不重要，重要的是他们能
hitting 92 beats a minute so I tend to
达到每分钟92拍的节奏。所以我
all 92 beats a minute before going on
上台前会听一个歌单，里面的歌都是每分钟92拍的。
stage I know that sounds like Madness
我知道这听起来像疯子乐队的风格，
you know and it's it may be it is but I
你知道的，而且…… 也许是这样，但我
think there's something about that
认为那种节奏对
Rhythm that just the audience that kind
观众来说有种魔力，它能让
that idea everyone kind of gets into
他们进入那种认知的最近速度，每个人都会不由自主地跟上
that Rhythm and when you look at the
那种节奏。你看那些
great public speakers they all seem to
伟大的公众演说家，他们似乎都能
be hitting that that rhythm of 92 beats
达到每分钟92拍的节奏。
a minute do you think Trump's a good
你觉得特朗普是个好的
public speaker yeah he's an excellent
公众演说家吗？当然，他是个优秀的
public speaker of course I don't know
公众演说家。我不明白
why people would have a problem
为什么人们会难以
admitting that it's I mean he's kind of
承认这一点。我的意思是，他有点像即兴
and he's freestyling it's like there's
发挥，好像没有任何事先
nothing planned this is this is
准备。这太
insane um yeah it's uh because he really
疯狂了。嗯，是的，因为他比
facts and figures than most politicians
大多数政客更注重夸张的叙事和情感，而不是事实和数据。
I mean it's a it's you know there's a
你知道，有一种
theory that this is all Gwen Stefani's
说法是这一切都是格温·史蒂芬妮的
fault what do you mean okay so Donald
错。什么意思？好吧，唐纳德·
Trump was pres was hosting the
特朗普当时是总统，主持《
Apprentice uh and Gwen Stefani was on uh
学徒》，而格温·史蒂芬妮当时在《
America's Got Talent or one of the
美国达人秀》或其他节目中。
singing shows maybe it was fact anyone
或许是某个
one of those big singing shows he found
大型歌唱节目，他
out she was getting paid more than him
发现她收入比他高，
and so he wanted to build his relevance
所以他想提升自己的影响力，于是
right so he decided Well I know I'll run
他决定：好吧，我知道了，我要竞选
for president I'll become incredibly
总统，这样就能在三个月内变得非常
relevant for like three months he's a
有影响力，他是个
contender he's whatever and then you
候选人，随便什么都行，然后
drop out the race no problem at all so
退出竞选，完全没问题。于是
he hires all those people in Plaza and
他在广场雇佣了所有人，然后
he comes down the gold escalator and he
他走下金色的自动扶梯，发表了
does the speech and great okay nothing
演讲，一切都很顺利，没什么大不了的。
he then goes and
之后，他去参加了
does the first make America great again
第一次“让美国再次伟大”
rally and they've got foot job him
集会，有人拍下了他
walking up the steps and he sees like
走上台阶的画面，他看到大约
10,000 people all
一万人都在
chanting and there's the
高喊口号，他
realization oh oh this could be
意识到：哦，这可能是
real it's kind of a yeah I think that's
真的。嗯，
I think that's stani did it get
我想这就是斯坦尼（Stani）的感受，
her I was the reason I was I was talking
我之所以谈论
about business is because because this
商业，是因为这是一个
is don't have a CEO it's a podcast about
没有首席执行官的播客，这是一个关于
business is is because you taught me
商业的播客，因为你上次间接地教了我一些东西，
something that I've now developed and I
我现在开发了一些东西，我
call myself no man's land which is that
称之为…… 我自己称之为“无人区”，指的是
moment when you make a decision to leave
你决定离开
the comfort and security of your
舒适和安全的职业身份，比如
Endeavor what whatever it is you were
你之前在Endeavor或其他公司从事的
working in marketing and then like I
营销工作，然后就像我
always reference how objectively insane
经常提到的那样，
it was for you to leave that and go and
你放弃这一切，去当
become a comedian and I've I've dubbed
一名喜剧演员，这在客观上是多么疯狂。我把这段时期称为“
that no man's land that sort of six to
无人区”，也就是六到
12 months of looking a bit stupid of
十二个月的“无人区”，这段时期你会显得有点傻，
losing your friends losing you know I
失去朋友，失去……你知道，我把
refer to these five buckets in life you
人生中的五个“桶”称为
have your knowledge skills your network
知识、技能、人脉、
your resources and your reputation and
资源和声誉。
when you go into No Man's Land you fill
当你进入“无人区”时，你填满了
the first two buckets of your Knowledge
知识
and Skills but you empty the last three
和技能这两个“桶”，但你却清空了后三个：失去人脉、
you lose your network you lose your
失去
resources often you lose your reputation
资源，通常还会失去声誉（
whatever that was at the time but you
无论当时你的声誉如何）。你
fill these two buckets you made that for
填满了知识和技能这两个“桶”，但你出于
whatever reason decision to leave a
某种原因决定离开
normal life and go and tell jokes for no
正常的生活，去不拿工资地讲笑话。
money some people for some reason and
有些人出于某种原因……
I've seen consistently on this podcast
我经常在这个播客里看到，
like Darren Brown who was had a great
比如达伦·布朗，他原本拥有非常美好的
professional life ahead of him and
职业生涯，却
decided to go do card tricks on tables
决定去布里斯托尔的桌子上表演纸牌魔术。
in Bristol for 10 years I what is it
十年了，
about these people that's making them I
这些人身上到底有什么特质让他们如此成功？我
think they've had the realization right
觉得他们已经意识到了，没错，
they've they've had the confucious
他们经历了孔子顿悟的
moment every man has two lives and he
时刻——每个人都有两次生命，
second begins when he realizes is he
第二次生命始于他意识到自己
only has
只有
one and the good is the enemy of the
一次生命之时，而“好”是“
best cuz you know when people are on
最好”的敌人。你知道，当人们在
podcast like this that moment looks like
播客节目里谈到这一点时，那一刻看起来就像是
bravery but I I wonder if to you and
勇气。但我很好奇，对你来说，
when you quit your sort of marketing job
当你辞掉营销工作的时候，是不是也经常会
no there's plenty of 4:00 in the morning
在凌晨四点惊呼：“
ah what have I done this seems this
啊，我到底做了什么？这看起来太
seems crazy especially when you really
疯狂了！”尤其是当你真的崩溃的
kind of when you break because when you
时候。因为当你
leave as well you don't have like an
离开的时候，你不会留下一个
hour of great stuff of like that you've
小时的精彩段子，你只会留下
written you've got like 20 minutes of
二十分钟的
stuff that you kind of look back on and
素材，然后回头看看，觉得它们有点像
go it's kind of joke shaped there's
笑话，里面确实有点
something there but really it's it's
东西，但实际上，这太
insane yeah but I think that's great I
疯狂了。是的，但我认为这很棒。我
think failure is one of the great gifts
认为失败是单口喜剧的一大馈赠，
failure as a standup because you write
作为一名单口喜剧演员，你会和失败成为朋友，因为你写了
so many things that don't work you write
很多不成功的东西。
so many jokes that you think oh this is
很多笑话你觉得“哦，这肯定
going to be great and then you tell it
很棒”，结果讲完之后
and the audience go no that isn't
观众却说“不，这
anything guess again and that idea of
没什么，再猜猜”。这种“失败”的想法
frowned upon in our society we don't let
在我们的社会里似乎不太受欢迎。我们不让
kids fail we don't let kids lose at
孩子失败，不让孩子在
sports we don't let you know that it
运动中输，我们不会告诉你失败是什么滋味。这
it's it's really silly because you're
真的很傻，因为你实际上是
sort of teaching them if if everyone's a
在教他们，如果每个人都是
winner then you don't learn how to lose
赢家，你就学不到如何面对失败。而
and to learn how to lose gracefully is
学会优雅地接受失败，这难道不是
that's a great skill to have isn't it
一项很棒的技能吗？
and and you kind of you know it checks
而且，它还能让你反思
your ego and you you some not everything
自己的自尊心。人生并非事事如意，
it's okay so you you test it and it's a
这很正常。所以，你要去尝试，这能
good test of how much you want something
很好地检验你对某件事的渴望程度。比如，你遇到一个糟糕的工作，然后心想“
and well I'm never doing that again or
我再也不干了”，或者
you have a terrible gig and go well you
你遇到一个糟糕的工作，然后心想“好吧，
know you you lose or you
你输了，你
learn you develop your relationship with
学到了东西，你发展了你与工作的关系”。
other day and it really stuck with me
前几天有人跟我说过一句话，我一直记在心里：
that you need you know I worked in Telly
你需要……你知道，我曾经在……工作 我在电视上工作了
celles for a couple of years and it
几年，这
really helped me develop my relationship
真的帮助我建立了
with the answer no and so now in life I
与“不”这个答案的关系。所以现在，我
I think I have a much healthier
觉得我对“
relationship with the word no because
不”这个字的态度健康多了。因为
for me in call in it's that the law of
对我来说，在
averag is where in the call center all
呼叫中心工作时，遵循平均法则，被拒绝就意味着离成功更
it meant was that I was one step closer
近了一步。
to getting the yes so I'd get you know
你知道，
you get loads of NOS in a row and you
你会连续听到很多“不”，然后
sit there and go [__] know this next
坐在那里，心里想着：我知道下一
guy is going to buy these [__] double
个人肯定会买这些双层
glazing and I think at at 16 years old I
玻璃窗。我觉得我在16岁的时候就
developed that relationship with no
建立了这种与“不”的关系，在我看来，
which me meant in my head that was
这意味着
getting me closer to a positive outcome
我离成功更近了一步。
lots of kids don't have that these these
现在很多孩子都没有这种经历，
days because we Shield them from no no
因为我们把他们保护起来，不让他们听到“不”。“不”
for me it was building some kind of
对我来说是一种自尊心的打击，它就像在我身上锻炼了一块
muscle in me I don't but self-esteem on
肌肉。我并不认为自尊心
its own like confidence without
本身就是一种自信，没有
confidence is
自信就是
madness it's Madness you you have to
疯狂，真的就是疯狂。你必须
give the world irrefutable proof you are
给世界无可辩驳的证据，证明你就是
who you say you are right so you you
你说的那个人，你是对的。所以，你
release a comedy special or whatever you
发行一部喜剧特辑或者其他什么东西。
go yeah that's me that's what I do the
对，那就是我，那就是我做的，
new tour that's me that's what I do it's
新的巡演，那就是我，那就是我做的，
it's irrefutable evidence right I am who
这是无可辩驳的证据，对吧？我就是我
I say I am and I think that idea of
所说的我。我认为那种把负面因素都排除掉的想法是行不通的，我的意思是，
can't just I mean I mean you can but
你可以这么做，但
then I think we're I think it's very
我觉得我们这样做很
cruel I think we're being kind on the
残酷，我觉得我们
wrong time scale to people
对别人的善意用错了时间尺度。
if you're kind you want to be kind to
如果你善良，你想善待
your kids right I want to be kind to my
你的孩子，对吧？我想善待我的
kids what do my kids want well they want
孩子。我的孩子想要什么？他们想要
McDonald's and they want ice cream and
麦当劳，他们想要冰淇淋，
they want to watch TV and play video
他们想要看电视，玩电子
games well okay Downstream are some fat
游戏。好吧，但下游是一些又胖又
stupid
笨的
kids who wants fat stupid kids no one so
孩子，谁想要又胖又笨的孩子？没人想要。所以
you have to be kind to their potential
你必须善待他们的潜力，善待他们未来的样子，对吧？
that involves you know broccoli and
这包括西兰花、
homework there boring going on a walk
作业（虽然很无聊）、散步、
doing some exercise
做一些运动，
okay but but you're being kind later and
好吧，但你是在以后善待他们。
I think that it's very easy to see that
我认为，
when you're a parent uh and it's hard to
当你为人父母时，很容易理解这一点，但很难在
see that with an 18-year-old that's
一个18岁的年轻人身上理解这一点。 也许这就是我之前说的，
being kind to you in 24 hours I guess
在24小时内善待自己，这有点难。我想这和
seeing the potential in in someone
看到别人身上的潜力，看到自己身上的潜力，
seeing the potential in yourself in a
看到
child in anyone but in yourself that's
孩子身上的潜力，看到任何人身上的潜力，但就是看到自己身上的潜力。这就像是说，嗯，
could be incredible in 20 years time cuz
20年后你可能会变得很了不起，因为那种感觉……
it's it's the um I suppose what's the
嗯，我想，
the opposite of gratitude it's
感恩的反义词是什么？是
resentment and who had the Great Line
怨恨。
nature had the great line on resentment
自然界有一句关于怨恨的名言，
he said if you think someone's ruined
他说，如果你认为有人毁了
your life you're
你的生活，你是对的，那就是
you like that's a mic drop isn't it
你自己。这简直一针见血，不是吗？这真是一句至理名言。
that's such a great line and you know
你知道，
gratitude is the cure for that there's a
感恩是治愈怨恨的良药。关于“权利感”有一个
there's a great definition of
很棒的定义，那就是
entitlement uh uh which is where you are
你
now and where you want to be if you want
现在所处的位置和你想要达到的位置。如果你想为此
to do something about it that's
做些什么，那就是雄心壮志。
ambition where you are now where you
你现在所处的位置和你
want to be if you think that's someone
想要达到的位置，如果你认为那是
else's
别人的
problem that's
问题，那就是
entitlement and I think if we're
权利感。我想，如果我们
honest there's always a little bit of
诚实一点…… 总会有些这样的情况
that going on like there's a lot of
发生，比如我们这
people in my industry that would you
行里很多人都
know that their career isn't where they
觉得自己的事业没达到预期，然后就想“
think it should be and ah I need to get
啊，我得换个
agent really you think that might be the
经纪人了”。你觉得这可能是
problem remember there's a great story
问题所在吗？记得有个很棒的故事，
of uh I wasn't there but uh David tell
呃，我当时不在场，但大卫·泰尔（David Tell）
is sort of the comedians comedian is
是
works out in New York late night uh he's
纽约深夜脱口秀的喜剧界泰斗，他
I mean really one of the greats one of
真的是喜剧界最伟大的人物之一，
the one of the most influential voices
最具影响力的声音之一。
in comedy and these guys backstage were
后台有人在抱怨
like moaning about their
他们的经纪人，他无意中听到了他们的
this conversation it's going on for far
对话，而且持续了太久，然后
too long and he just he oh be funnier
他就说：“哦，要更有趣才行。”
it's often very simple that stoic thing
通常，道理很简单，就是那种坚忍不拔的处事方式：去做你真正应该
be doing just do that I'm not sure I
做的事。我不确定我是否
approve of portfolio sort of uh working
赞同那种“作品集”式的、同时做
the idea of having lots of different
很多不同
things that you do because
事情的做法，因为如果
really you going to do comedy part-time
你真的打算兼职做喜剧，或者一半时间做
what you're going to do half comedy and
喜剧，
half novel writing oh so you're going to
一半时间写小说，那该怎么办呢？ 所以你要跟我
compete I'm doing it 100% of the time
竞争，而我可是百分之百投入，
and you think you can compete 50% of the
你觉得你只能跟我竞争一半时间？
time all the best let's see how you do
祝你好运，咱们走着瞧。
you're never going to get to the top of
你永远不可能靠一半时间就爬到金字塔顶端，对吧？
right yeah and there'll probably be a
没错，而且正如
lot of resentment as you say an
你所说，可能会有很多怨恨。那种自以为是、觉得自己高人一等的想法，
entitlement be you know be be a
你知道，就是想成为某个领域的
specialist it's one of the favorite
专家。
parts of my previous conversation that I
我上次跟你谈话时，你谈到
the world doesn't need more people that
世界不需要更多
are [__] in physics and it really helped
物理一窍不通的人，那段话让
me understand a lot of things I also
我受益匪浅，也让我理解了很多事情。之后
then shortly after Met Richard Branson
不久，我在纽约遇到了理查德·布兰森，
in New York and he's the most you know
他简直是授权
incredible delegator he's not trying to
大师。他不会试图去精通
get good at things that he's not good at
自己不擅长的领域，
he's built his whole business and life
他整个事业和人生都建立
on realizing what he's [__] at and just
在认识到自己的弱项并把它们交给
handing that over to other people
其他人的基础上。
whereas so many people are fighting to
而很多人却在苦苦挣扎，试图
polish something that they're not so
完善自己不
good at yeah I think knowing who you are
擅长的东西。是啊，我觉得了解自己
is quite important for that isn't it
很重要，不是吗？
it's like being honest about it like
就像坦诚地说“
well I'm not good at that but I can do
我不太擅长这个，但我能做到
this it's hard to know who you are
这个”，虽然很难了解自己是谁，
though clouded you want to be yeah it's
你想成为什么样的人，但方向却很模糊。嗯，是的，这需要
uh it takes a bit of
一些
time I'm not sure whether we're not kind
时间。我不确定我们是不是有点
of rushing people on that a little
催促大家了。我
bit I'm i i s often think of like the
经常会想到
listeners to this show right so like
这个节目的听众，对吧？
certainly the younger ones of kind of
尤其是年轻的听众，他们会想“我
going well do I need to know now who I
现在就需要知道我是谁，
am and what I want to do exactly it's no
我想做什么吗？”答案是：不，
you could you know try a few different
你可以尝试一些不同的
things see what you like because I think
事情，看看你喜欢什么。因为我觉得，
that thing when you get into the stream
当你找到自己
that you're meant to be in it just feels
应该去的方向时，一切都会变得
very easy it's like you're not you're
非常轻松，就像你不再
not you know swimming against the tide
逆流而上，而​​是被潮流裹挟着
along I love what I do now but I often
前进。我喜欢我现在做的事情，但我经常会
question whether I should go be like a
问自己，我是否应该去做
DJ or do musical theater or something
DJ，或者去演音乐剧什么的。
what me do what I can answer that
我可以回答
question for you that's a bit of luck no
你的这个问题，这有点运气成分。不，
no you [__]
不，你他妈的…… 你
shouldn't what what you think you maybe
不应该……你觉得你也许
should do musical theater who what are
应该去演音乐剧？
you having a panic attack what what are
你是不是恐慌发作了？
you talking
你在说什么？是
about what would make you think that I I
什么让你这么想？我
bought some DJ equipment and I spent
买了一些DJ设备，花了
about a year learning and I thought I
一年左右的时间学习，然后我想，我他妈的
[__] love doing this great you've got
太喜欢做这个了！太好了！你有
hobby you've got a hobby not
爱好，你有爱好，不是
everything's a business I know it's di
所有事都要变成生意。我知道现在都是
over CEO and everything you do you think
CEO，你做的每件事你都想着“
oh maybe we can make a few quid out of
哦，也许我们可以从中赚点钱”。
this no stop it what are you talking
不，别说了！你在说什么？
about you know who's you know who's
你知道
being a DJ right now there's someone
现在谁在做DJ吗？现在就有人在
right now in their bedroom they've been
卧室里，他们今天已经在
there for 12 hours already today and
那里待了12个小时了，
they're just loving it and they're
他们非常享受，他们
putting everything into it they're
倾注了所有心血，他们把
putting the work you put into the
你在
podcast into
播客上投入的精力都投入到
DJing let them have that it's nice to
DJ工作中。让他们享受吧！
in life and for some people that's work
生活中能有一些让你心流的事情是件好事，对有些人来说是工作，
and for some people that's a hobby and
对有些人来说是爱好，
and some some of us are very lucky and
而我们中的一些人很幸运，
we get to do it in a few different
可以在几种不同的
things so I play a little bit
事情上做到这一点。比如我打一点
tennis I don't think I'm going to get
网球，我不认为…… 今年我打算去
the wild card at Wimbledon this year
温布尔登拿外卡，不过
there I've given up on that it's just a
我已经放弃了，这只是个
hobby and listen I mean you might be the
爱好。听着，我的意思是，你或许会成为
next Calvin Harris I might be steering
下一个卡尔文·哈里斯，我可能把
you in the wrong direction you might be
你引向了错误的方向，你或许很
incredible but stop it stop it just do
了不起，但别这样，别这样，就做
this this is great this is
这件事吧。这很棒，这就够了，这很
enough it's is lovely you're talking to
美好。你在和
the most interesting people I mean
最有趣的人交谈，我是说，在座各位都很棒。
present company accepted but you you
你
know you speak to all these different
知道，你和来自
people from different worlds and it's
不同领域的形形色色的人交谈，这就够了，对吧？
it's this is enough right how do you
你怎么
know if it isn't enough well I want to
知道这还不够呢？我想
talk to you about quitting because
和你谈谈放弃的事，因为会有
there's going to be a cohort of people
一群人
that listen to them I meet them I met a
听你的，我见过他们，
lot of them last night at a show I was
昨晚我在一个演出上就遇到了很多。
doing and they are working in finance
他们在金融行业工作，
and they'll tell me their job then
他们会告诉我他们的工作，然后给
they'll show me their hobby on their
我看他们手机上的爱好，
phone and their face lights up when they
当他们
show me their I don't know their Pap and
给我看他们的……我不知道他们的……Pap and
mashe business or whatever it is on
Mashe生意，或者其他什么
their phone what's the great line it's
手机上的东西时，他们的脸上会露出笑容。最精彩的一句话是……
the uh you know if you if you want to
你知道，如果你想
find out what you should do in
知道……
life what do you think about all the
人生中你该做什么？你一直在想什么？
time that's your
你的
[Music]
[音乐]
god what working in the city with a
天哪，穿着
shirt and tie on at JP Morgan or
衬衫打着领带在摩根大通之类的公司上班？
something no but no one's thinking about
不，没人会一直想着
that all the time you know so what do
这些，你知道吗？所以你一直在
you what do you think about all the time
想什么？
what are you what are you engaged in all
你一直在做什么？
the time like if it's if it's football
比如，
if you're absolutely obsessed by
如果你痴迷于
football well something in that industry
足球，那么足球行业的工作就适合
is going to be the job for you because
你，因为你对它如此
you're obsessed by that and that's what
痴迷，
you think about all the time so the um
你一直在想着它。所以，
the idea of quitting quitting is quite
放弃的想法很
interesting
有意思，
because oh the things that you won't do
因为哦，你将无法体验很多事情。
like if you're going to have an
如果你想拥有
interesting life you can't have all the
精彩的人生，你就无法拥有所有
other interesting lives you would have
其他精彩的人生，对吧？
had right so there's all the
所以，有很多
counterfactuals of the different sliding
不同的可能性，比如，
you know if you're going to be an
如果你想成为一名
Olympian you're going to have to give up
奥运选手，你就必须放弃
an awful lot of stuff like you're not
很多东西，比如你
really going to have a childhood in the
可能无法拥有童年。 从
traditional sense but you're going to be
传统意义上讲，你会成为
an Olympian great and if you if you're
一名伟大的奥运选手，但如果你想
going to be an academic then you're
成为一名学者，那你
probably not going to be having to go to
可能就不用参加
as many parties okay well that's you
那么多派对了。好吧，你
know there's there's no Solutions only
知道，没有完美的解决方案，只有权衡取舍。
trade-offs you know Thomas S isn't
托马斯·S，不是吗？
it you have to make a lot of trade-offs
你必须做出很多权衡，
because not only you know are you on the
因为你不仅
road 300 days a year but you have so
一年有300天都在路上，而且还有
much opportunity there's so many things
很多机会，很多事情摆在
being offered to you to do movies why
你面前，比如拍电影，为什么
don't you try and be an actor or why
不尝试当演员？或者为什么
don't you write five more books or why
不再写五本书？或者为什么
don't you do I don't know a comic
不…… 哦，我不知道喜剧、音乐
comical musical or whatever it might be
剧之类的，
why don't you become a DJ DJ and musical
你为什么不去当DJ呢？DJ和音乐
theater those are my two prime loves um
剧是我的两大爱好。嗯，是的，
yeah I mean there's there's a few
我的意思是，有一些，但
there's not as many as you would think I
没有你想象的那么多。
don't no one's banging down my door
没人会来敲我的门
saying you want to be in a movie um and
说你想演电影。嗯，
I don't know if I'd be I don't know if
我不知道我能不能演好，我不知道我能不能演好。我不知道，我的
I'd be great at that I don't know I mean
意思是，
listen I like getting out my comfort
听着，我喜欢走出舒适
zone and you know opportunities come
区，你知道，机会总会来的，
along and sometimes you you get offed a
有时候你会接到一个
TV show you go well give it a go why not
电视节目的邀约，你会想，好吧，试试看，为什么不呢？
um but I think sticking to what you do
嗯，但我认为坚持做自己擅长的事，那种坚韧不拔的精神，
that stoic thing has really paid
真的会带来丰厚的
dividends that really has paid off and I
回报，真的会有回报。我
think you have to listen to that you
认为你必须听从这个建议。你
know and I see other Comics you know
知道，我看到其他一些喜剧演员，你知道，我
mentioning no names there's some great
就不点名了，有些很棒的单口
standup Comics that were like absolutely
喜剧演员，他们以前非常
amazing and they're doing five other
出色，现在却同时做五六
things now and they've lost a yard of
件事，他们的事业发展
pace and for me that feels crazy like
速度慢了下来。对我来说，这感觉很疯狂，
you've because I'm looking at it going
因为我看着…… 你会想，
you've got the best job in the world why
你拥有世界上最好的工作，为什么还要
are you allowing yourself to be
让自己
distracted because ultimately it's going
分心呢？因为归根结底，这注定是一份
to be hard work you know ultimately I
艰苦的工作。你知道，我的
mean people can see it I suppose that
意思是，人们都能看出来。我想，
the you know something costs more like a
有些东西价格昂贵，比如
a Ferrari cost a lot of money cuz a lot
法拉利，因为它需要投入大量的心血。
of work goes into that thing there a the
一件
beautiful handmade made Louis Vuitton
精美的手工路易威登
thing is it's going to be expensive
包包，它价格不菲，
because a lot of work went into it
因为它凝聚了无数的心血。
people understand that I sort of feel
人们都明白这一点。我对演出也有类似的感受。
the same about shows you're going to see
你去看
a show you wow that really took some
一场演出，你会惊叹：哇，这真的花了不少
time every single line in that is
时间，每一句台词都
brilliant he's not wasting any time it's
精彩绝伦，他没有浪费任何时间，
no there's no fat it's just it's a lot
没有丝毫赘肉，只是需要付出很多
work when people look at you and they
努力。当人们看着你，
look at successful individuals they
看着那些成功人士时，他们会
think oh they just must be innately
想：哦，他们一定天生就有一种
motivated in some way that I'm not well
动力，而我没有。嗯，
I do think that's it's slightly unfair
我认为
that we think about luck in a very fixed
我们以一种非常固定的方式来看待运气有点不公平。
way right so Barbie and Oppenheimer are
芭比和奥本海默
great to talk about this right so people
很适合谈论这个话题。人们
see Margo Robbie and they go well she's
看到玛格特·罗比…… 他们会说，她
just lucky right she was born she's that
只是运气好，对吧？她天生
beautiful right she's so beautiful
丽质，对吧？她太美了，
people can't see how good an actress she
人们根本看不出她演技有多好，
is right people just can't because she's
对吧？人们就是看不出来，因为她就像个
just like sort of this stunning thing
惊艳的尤物。
and and you look Oppenheimer right no
你看奥本海默，对吧？没
one thinks a he so lucky born with an IQ
人觉得他运气好，智商
170 a and born with a work ethic because
170，而且天生就勤奋努力，因为
a work ethic is heritable right so he
勤奋是可以遗传的，对吧？所以他
was born incredibly clever and an
天生就非常聪明，而且
incredible work ethic right and no one
非常勤奋，对吧？没人
thinks of him as being lucky but they
觉得他运气好，但人们却
think of her is being lucky it's weird
觉得她运气好。这很奇怪，对吧？这在
thing right that's odd in our perception
我们对运气的认知里很奇怪，有
of of luck and how much is how much is
多少是
your factory settings you know this it's
你的“出厂设置”？你知道，这
always I've talked to you about this
总是……我以前跟你说过，
before but it's always like some some
但总是……一些
[__] uh if someone's very successful
胡扯……呃，如果一个人非常成功，
you either go wow incredible Talent OR
你要么说“哇，真是天才”，要么说“哦，
oh he works so hard no always both
他真努力”，不，总是两者兼有，
together always both
总是两者
together and or like you said earlier
兼有，或者就像你之前说的，
maybe a bit pathological in some way
也许在某种程度上有点病态，
which I don't know whether you'd put
我不知道你是否还会把“
Talent bucket again you put the
天赋”归类，你还是把“
pathological the work ethic the the
病态”归类吧。 工作态度和
striving a lot of that is
奋斗精神很多都是可以
heritable you know so what what are you
遗传的，你知道吗？所以你打算怎么办？
going to do I think when you when you
我觉得当你
see luck in that way I think you become
这样看待运气的时候，你会变得
much more forgiving of
更加宽容。
okay it's quite crazy this idea of luck
好吧，运气这个概念确实很疯狂，
i' think been thinking a lot about it
我
lately I was reading some stories about
最近一直在思考这个问题。我读了一些故事，比如，如果
um even the asteroid hitting Earth if it
小行星撞击地球晚
had been a minute later than the
一分钟，
dinosaurs would still be here and the
恐龙现在可能还活着。还有
story of Nagasaki and Hiroshima being
长崎和广岛被
bombed because one guy went to Kyoto 20
轰炸的故事，因为有个人20年前去了京都，
years earlier and he really liked it so
他很喜欢那里，所以
he told president truma not to bomb it
他告诉特鲁玛总统不要轰炸京都。
and if he hadn't been on holiday there
如果他
with his wife then Kyoto would have been
当时没有和妻子在那里度假，京都就会被
hit by the nuclear bomb and then they
原子弹炸到。然后他们
went over kakuru I think a city in Japan
飞越了日本的一个城市——隐谷，
and that had a cloud so they s [__] it
那里有一片云，所以他们就说，算了，
we'll go bomb Hiroshima and 100,000
我们去轰炸广岛吧。结果
people over there lost their lives and
那里有10万人丧生，每一代人都失去了生命。
lost you you think these tiny little
你会想，世界上时时刻刻都在发生这些看似微不足道的小事，就像
all times kind of like this this idea of
这个概念一样……
the butterfly effect shaping our world
蝴蝶效应塑造着我们的世界，
and it can make you feel a little bit
它在某种程度上会让你感到
powerless in some way because if I'm the
无力，因为如果我是那个人，
you know if if someone's holiday can be
你知道，如果一个人的假期决定了
the difference between me being alive or
我的生死，是的，
dead yeah it's you know it's very
你知道，这很难理解，我们
difficult to to you know we we always
总是
you know think about the first order
想着我们行为的第一层
effects of what we do not the second and
影响，而不是第二层和
third order effects yeah so yeah I mean
第三层影响，是的，我的意思是，这信息量
that's a that's a lot to that's a lot to
很大，要理解“
take in with this idea of luck in mind
运气”这个概念，
mind personal responsibility seems to
个人责任似乎与运气截然相反，
conversation of luck which is how much
那就是我能多大程度上掌控
can I control where I'm going in my life
自己的人生方向，我
how much control do I have how much
拥有多少控制权，我应该付出多少努力去争取
positive outcomes yeah well that's
积极的结果，是的，这就是
agency you should you should strive to
自主性，你应该努力将
have the locus of control within
控制权掌握在
yourself like so there's there's
自己手中，就像品格
character and there's reputation and
和声誉一样，
reputation is what the world thinks of
声誉是世人对
you and character is what you know about
你的看法，品格是你对
yourself and your self-esteem should be
自己的了解，你的自尊应该
Lar based on your character and a little
主要基于你的品格，也部分
bit based on reputation because
基于声誉，因为
reputation you could you could take a
声誉可能会
hit every now and then you get canceled
时不时地受到打击。 你偶尔会被“取消”，嗯，大概
once in a while well once every 18
每18个
months well hang on the the Netflix
月一次吧。等等，我的Netflix
special drops today so I imagine I'm
特辑今天上线，所以我估计我
being canceled right now somewhere how
现在正在某个地方被“取消”呢。
have you come to deal with that because
你是怎么应对这种情况的？因为
as a comedian you guys get it worse than
作为喜剧演员，你们受到的“取消”比
anybody I don't know if we get it worse
任何人都严重。我不知道我们是不是
than anyone I think we're sort of the
比任何人都严重，我觉得我们就像“
canary in the mind it's it's I don't
金丝雀”一样，是那种……我不
know I sort of view it as respectability
知道，我把它看作是“体面”
is a prison and the gates are open and
是一座监狱，大门敞开，
people are desperate to be
人们都渴望
inside right I I'm not a respectable guy
进去。我不是个“体面”的人，
I tell very edgy out there jokes and
我讲的笑话非常尖锐、离经叛道，
jokes are like magnets they attract some
笑话就像磁铁，它们会吸引一些
people I've got a big following I've got
人。我有很多粉丝，
a lot of people that watch my shows and
很多人看我的节目，
and they really enjoy it and light
他们真的很喜欢。就像
magnets they the jokes attract people
磁铁一样，笑话会吸引人，也会
and they repel people some people are
排斥人。有些人
repelled by my jokes and they think
觉得我的笑话很糟糕，很反感。
they're terrible I'm not for everyone I
我不是每个人都喜欢的，我
think you have to accept that and you
觉得你必须接受这一点。你
know it's it's when it comes out on
知道，当它在
Netflix when it drops DRS that's when it
Netflix上线的时候，当它正式上线的时候，一切就都明朗了。
kind of the pathogen escapes the lab
病原体从实验室逃逸，
because people that didn't pay to see
因为那些没花钱来看的人
this are suddenly exposed to it someone
突然接触到了它。有人
puts a clip somewhere and goes this ban
把视频片段放到某个地方，然后说“禁掉
this filth
这个垃圾”。
okay Banning stuff it's like I sort of
好吧，禁掉东西，我感觉这有点像是
view Council culture as the new and this
新时代的“委员会文化”。这
isn't saying criticism isn't valid you
并不是说批评无效，你
can criticize ideas but you cancel
可以批评观点，但你可以“取消”
people and I think the cancel culture
别人。我觉得“取消文化”就像是
thing I think it's the new book burning
新时代的焚书，
it's no different the people that burnt
没什么区别。想想那些
The Beatles records in the 60s how do
在60年代烧掉披头士唱片的人，
they feel now you feel like a dummy I
他们现在感觉如何？你觉得自己像个傻瓜？我
bet they feel like dummies it's like and
敢打赌他们觉得自己像个傻瓜。这就像……
and obviously the basket of things that
显然，
are acceptable and unacceptable change
可接受和不可接受的事物范围会
and EB and flow through time but really
随着时间推移而改变和变化。但实际上，
it's it's uh you know I'm I'm a creature
你知道，我是个
of my time I'm going to I'm going to
时代的产物。我会
tell these jokes and if they get big
讲这些笑话，如果大家
laughs then then great have you always
笑得很开心，那就太好了。你一直
had this perspective or is this
都有这种观点吗？还是
over time no I think I think there's um
随着时间的推移逐渐形成的？不，我觉得……我觉得……我经历过很多
I think that adversity I've been
逆境，我被“
canceled quite a few times and there's I
取消”过很多次。 有好几次，我都
try and see the positives in life right
试着从生活中看到积极的一面。
so adversity is a filter and you find
逆境就像一个过滤器，让你
out who your friends are and who stands
看清谁是真正的朋友，谁会
by you and who's you know who's ride or
支持你，谁是
die great turns out got loads of great
生死与共的挚友。结果发现我有很多
friends and a couple of people fell by
好朋友，也有一些人渐渐疏远了。
the wayside and great I don't have to
没关系，我不用
waste any time on them
在他们身上浪费时间，
because everyone loves you when you're
因为当你举办派对的时候，每个人都喜欢你；
thrown a party but in the tough times
但在艰难时期，人们就没那么
you're a bit more difficult to love and
喜欢你了。
if people stand by you then then they're
如果有人在你身边支持你，那他们就是
friends that's that's that's what it is
朋友，就是这样。
you friendship is such an important
友谊非常重要，
thing it's something that we don't
我们常常忽略它。
really think about we think about a lot
我们更多地考虑
about our partners in life and our
伴侣、
children and that side of family
孩子以及家庭关系，但
friendship for me is such an important
对我来说，友谊非常重要，
thing it's such a huge part of my life
它是我生命中非常重要的一部分。
and really when you think about it why
仔细想想，为什么
why do why is comedy having this moment
喜剧现在这么火？
well because comedian it's a little bit
因为喜剧有点
like a friendship right there's there's
像友谊，
a there's no
没有
filter and really your best friend is
滤镜。你最好的朋友就是
the person you have the least filter
你最坦诚、最
with your deepest darkest you share
深切地表达自己想法的人。 你最黑暗的时刻，
you're open and a colleague you quite a
你坦诚相待；而你的同事，你却有
lot of filter and someone you meet the
很多伪装；你在公交车站遇到的某个人，也有
tons of filter right Comics kind there's
很多伪装。喜剧演员就不一样了，他们
no there's no filter you see Chappelle
没有伪装。你看查普尔
on stage he's it's him great you see
在舞台上，他就是他，太棒了；你看
Chris Rock On Stage that's him it's like
克里斯·洛克在舞台上，那就是他，
you feel
你会感觉与他们建立了
connected
联系，
lovely there's really something in that
很棒。
idea of as you were saying there that
正如你刚才所说，这个
vulnerability and openness in the world
世界上真实、脆弱和坦诚如此匮乏，所以当
that when we encounter it we feel so
我们遇到这些时，会感到如此
connected to it because it caters to the
亲近，因为它满足了
demand that we have that's not being met
我们内心深处的需求，而这种
with Supply there's so much supply of
需求却无法得到满足。市面上充斥着太多
like filter girl on holiday in Hawaii
像“滤镜女孩”在夏威夷度假
drinking cocktail but it but in our sort
喝鸡尾酒那样的形象，但在我们的
of private and our secret lives there's
私人生活和秘密生活中，
very little um reflection of what we
我们私下里的想法很少在
lives in the world so when we hear
外界得到反映。所以，当我们听到
someone talking about their depression
有人谈论他们的抑郁症
or their mental health we go oh my God
或心理健康问题时，我们会惊呼“我的天哪”，这太
that you know can resonate or is this
能引起共鸣了。这难道
not why the podcast is so big why comedy
不是播客如此火爆、喜剧
so big at the moment because the the gap
如此受欢迎的原因吗？因为
between public and private discourse has
公共话语和私人话语之间的鸿沟
never been wider and we both were we're
从未如此之大。我们俩都…… 我们都
both living in that space we you go yeah
生活在那种境地，你去，是的，和
someone great and the you know the the
某个很棒的人进行一次真正的对话，你知道，被“
cancelling thing is is great but
取消”这件事本身很棒，但
really what happens I mean you could you
实际上会发生什么呢？我的意思是，你可以
can recalibrate it and just call it free
重新调整它，把它当作免费
publicity like people are talking about
宣传，就像人们在谈论
you well great
你一样，很好。
okay there's this thing called the
好吧，有一个叫做“
Eraser test which one of my guests
橡皮擦测试”的东西，我的一个嘉宾在节目开始
talked to me about before mord out where
前跟我谈到过，
he said if you could go back and he
他说，如果你能回到过去，他会
asked I think he asked or there was a
问，我想他是问的，或者说，有一项
study done where they asked people if
研究问人们，如果
they could go back in time and erase
他们可以回到过去，抹去
their most difficult moment would you
他们最艰难的时刻，你会
press the button and erase it and like
按下按钮把它抹掉吗？
these are like really traumatic events
这些都是非常痛苦的事件，
about 95% of people said they wouldn't
大约95%的人表示他们不会。
when you think about your most traumatic
想想你最痛苦的
moments of sort of being canceled or
时刻，比如被“取消”之类的，
I got um actually the last time I got
我得到的最好的建议是，实际上，上次我被“
canceled I found a friend of mine who's
取消”的时候，我找到了一个也
been cancelled and he said you've only
被“取消”过的朋友，他说
got you've only got to answer one
你只需要回答一个
question who's Jimmy
问题：吉米·卡是谁？
car uh any went no who's Jimmy KH I well
呃，不，吉米·卡是谁？嗯，
I'm edgy stand-up comedian
我有点另类。 脱口秀演员，
okay fine then you haven't got a
好吧，那你没
problem it's great and then another
问题，这很棒。然后
friend of mine just went well you need
我的另一个朋友说，你需要
to just rightsize this and I'm what
调整一下。我说，什么？什么？
what's you've got to rightsize it she
你得调整一下？她
said what's happened here you told a
说，发生了什么？你讲了个
joke and some people didn't like
笑话，有些人不喜欢。是啊，就是这样。
a deal when you put it like
你这么说，我觉得好像没什么大不了的。但
that and yet in the moment sometimes it
有时候，在那一刻，
feels you know
感觉就像
catastrophic but those hard times you
灾难一样。你
know you wouldn't erased the hard times
知道，你不会抹去那些艰难的时刻，
because again I would say and it's a
因为我会说，
great character and what they're saying
伟大的人物不可能一帆风顺。他们说的意思
thereby not erasing that moment is I'll
是，我不会抹去那一刻，我会
keep my character
保持我的风格。
thanks anxiety we talked about this last
谢谢焦虑，我们
time anxiety is it's a very interesting
上次也谈到了焦虑。焦虑是个很有意思的
thing I mean my kind of original thought
东西。我最初对
on anxiety was the it's the flip side of
焦虑的看法是，它是
Crea ity so you have a mind that is
创造力的另一面。你的大脑一直在
woring and that's given me every gift
运转，它给了我所有天赋，对吧？
write jokes and to to be funny or
写笑话的能力，搞笑的能力
whatever is from that I can't turn it
等等。 就是因为我的大脑无法停止运转，
off mind and sometimes at 4 in the
有时候凌晨四点，
morning when you got nothing to do that
即使你无所事事，它
mind is still woring so you get involved
仍然在运转，于是你开始进行
in counterfactuals you start to think of
反事实思考，开始思考
happened that haven't happened in life
生活中所有可能发生但尚未发生的事情。
and you know people are not worried
你知道，人们担心的不是
about falling off a cliff they're
掉下悬崖，而是
worried about jumping it's the madness
跳下去。这是我们每个人内心深处的疯狂，总是想着“
could happen and the worst case scenario
会发生什么？”、“最糟糕的情况是什么？”、“
and these terrible things and you allow
那些可怕的事情是什么？”，而你却任由这种想法占据你的思绪。
that to to get ahead of you I think the
我认为，
cure for it for me at the moment how I'm
目前我
managing my anxiety is giving myself
控制焦虑的方法是给自己安排
more to
更多的事情。
do because I think anxiety you're trying
因为我认为焦虑是试图
to solve a problem in the future now and
解决未来的问题，但
you can't because there's no problem in
你做不到，因为
the now the problem is in in the future
现在根本没有问题，问题在未来。
so you you you're kind of ahead there
所以你有点操之过急，试图
trying to trying to figure out something
弄明白一些事情，
because you there's a demand
因为你
for um for problem solving in the moment
现在需要解决问题，
and you don't have a problem fact think
而你并没有遇到问题。想想看，
of like people don't get depressed when
人们去健身房不会感到沮丧，对吧？
they go to the gym right if you're in
如果你在
the gym you can't be anxious while
健身房…… 锻炼的时候不能焦虑，
you're working out because you have an
因为你现在有
immediate problem I got lift this damn
眼下的问题要解决，比如“我得把这该死的压
thing off my chest you've got an
在心头”，你得
immediate thing to deal with you're in
立刻处理这件事，你正处于当下，
that moment so it's hard to be anxious
所以很难焦虑，
because you got something to do right
因为你现在有事可做。
right now if you're suffering with
如果你感到
anxiety and don't let your mind kind of
焦虑，就给自己找点事做，别让你的思绪飘到
drift into the future kind I suppose
未来。我觉得
it's quite sort of um
这有点像
Buddhist in a way is your anxiety
佛教的理念。你的焦虑是由
anything or is it just kind of a noise
什么引发的，还是只是
in the background I I don't think it is
背景噪音？我不这么认为。
I think you often I think I I think
我觉得你经常会有
there's an illusion that when you feel
一种错觉，以为
anxiety it's about this thing I think
焦虑是因为某件事。但实际上，我觉得
actually you've just got a a level of
你只是处于一种
anxiety and you will you know so if I've
焦虑状态，你知道，即使我
got nothing to worry about career-wise
没有什么事业或
or show wise or I'm not currently being
演出方面的担忧，或者我的节目没有被
canceled you might worry about the
取消，你也可能会担心
environment or you worry about your kids
环境问题，担心你的孩子，
or you worry about you know you'll worry
或者担心
about something else so I think you just
其他事情。所以我觉得它会依附于你
front of mind and you logically go oh
脑海中浮现的任何事物，然后你就会自然而然地想：哦
it's anxiety about this it isn't it's
是焦虑，不是，只是
anxiety do you think people know who you
焦虑。你觉得人们真正了解你吗？
are truly you know I I met with a CIA
你知道吗？几周前我见了一位中央情报局
agent a couple of weeks ago and he said
特工，他说
we have three lives we have our our
我们有三种生活：
secret life we have our private life and
秘密生活、私人生活和公众生活。
then we have our public life public life
公众生活就是
camera your private life might be what
镜头前穿着西装的那个人。你的私人生活可能是
your wife knows but then maybe your
你妻子所知道的，但你的
secret life is who you are when there's
秘密生活可能是你
like absolutely nobody there in your
完全独处时的样子，在你自己的
mind and in your own space do you think
内心世界里，在你自己的空间里。你觉得
people know who you are I think so I
人们真正了解你吗？我
think actually weirdly um this podcast
觉得……嗯，其实很奇怪，这个播客
is quite important in that you know
很重要，因为你知道，上
going on this going on Joe Rogan going
乔·罗根的节目，
on Modern wisdom and talking as myself
上现代智慧节目，以我自己的身份谈论这些，都
is very exposing uh and writing the book
非常坦诚。写《
before and after which is kind of a um
之前和之后》这本书，算是
autobiography but also a bit
自传，但也带点
self-helpy-ness
自助性质。
if we knew each other if we were having
如果我们彼此认识，如果我们一起吃
lunch you know for the listeners it's
午饭，你知道，对听众来说，这就像……
like this is yeah it's kind of what I'm
嗯，这就是我，
like and then I've got an ability to be
然后我还能
funny on stage which is another side of
在舞台上展现幽默，这是我的另一面。
me so I think that's like it's not it's
所以我觉得…… 就像
not inauthentic what I do on stage it's
我在舞台上的表现并非虚假，那只是
just like that's who I am in front of
我在
3,000 people that have all paid £30 to
3000名观众面前的真实写照，他们每人花了30英镑来看
entertained here we go what's the side
演出。好了，我们来谈谈
of view that your wife might know but we
你妻子可能知道但我们
don't well this this this is yeah you
不知道的观点。嗯，你
know you you're slightly more um I think
知道，你稍微……我觉得在这方面，
on this it's it's very much you take
你把……
uh it's not like doing a TV show to
嗯，这不像上电视节目
publicize something so if you go on you
宣传什么，所以如果你上节目，你
know gr you're very much like okay well
知道，你会说，好吧，
I've got three anecdotes and I'll get
我有三个轶事，我会讲出来，我会努力
laughs and then I'll try and snipe her
逗笑四个人，然后我会试着
in on the other guests and be funny and
挖苦其他嘉宾，让自己变得有趣，这
it's a it's very performative whereas
很像表演。而
this is performative but in a slightly
这个也是表演，但
different way where you're kind of going
方式略有不同，你会说，嗯，
well this is kind of what I think about
这就是我对世界的看法，这就是我
like inside my head and it's quite I
脑子里的想法，这很……我
don't know I suppose when you step back
不知道，我想当你…… 从那件事回来之后，感觉还
from it it's kind of okay well a lot of
不错，嗯，做了很多
self-help a lot of uh a lot of
自助，很多，嗯，很多，
uh I guess therapy a you that's that's
我想，心理治疗吧。这就是
what I'm like since we spoke last
我自从上次谈话以来的状态。
time is there anything you thought then
你当时的想法有没有什么现在
that you no longer believe I'm
不再相信了？我很
interested I'm asking that question
感兴趣，我问这个问题是
because my favorite question what was
因为我最喜欢的问题是：
the last thing you changed your mind
你最近一次改变主意是什么时候？
about um I think I've changed my mind
嗯，我想我
about environmentalism a little bit I
对环保主义的看法稍微改变了一些。
think I'm I absolutely acknowledge the
我完全承认这个
problem and I think the solution is just
问题，而且我认为解决方案就在
there I think it's I think it's
那里，我认为就是
splitting the atom I think we should all
原子裂变。我认为我们都应该……
be I think nuclear is kind of the is the
我认为核能是
future that's what we should be
未来，那是我们应该
investing in that's we've got an issue
投资的方向。我们现在面临的问题是，
that we have a system that is full of
我们的体制充斥着
politicians and we we haven't got
政客，而我们没有真正的
Statesman we need longer
政治家。我们需要更长远的
terms longer terms we need longer terms
任期，我​​们需要更长远的任期，
because we need people to make decisions
因为我们需要有人来做决定，
like everything's about um about rewards
一切都与回报有关，对吧？
right so what do we reward it's on a 5
那么我们奖励什么呢？它以
year cycle so no one's ever going to
五年为一个周期，所以永远不会有人
invest in nuclear because it's going to
投资核能，因为它需要…… 需要
take 20 years to pay off but they should
20年才能见效，但他们理应得到某种回报。
be rewarded for that somehow we need to
我们需要
find a way to reward politicians for
找到一种方法来奖励那些
what they did 20 years ago because if we
20年前做出贡献的政治家，因为如果我们这样
do that it's there there's a better
做，
future right and I I don't know if
未来就会更美好，对吧？我不知道
Britain doing it makes any difference
英国这样做是否真的会有什么不同，
like people often say well if Britain
就像人们常说的那样，英国这样做也没什么
does it it doesn't make any difference
区别，
because well China's not going to do it
因为中国不会这样做，
or India's not going to do it but you go
印度也不会这样做。但
well actually if we did it if we did
实际上，如果我们这样做，如果我们采取一些
something something radical and went all
激进的措施，全面发展
nuclear there been incredible examples
核能，那么就会有令人难以置信的榜样可以向
to set to the rest of the world here's
世界其他国家展示。这就是
what I do here's my you want to hear my
我的想法，这就是我的方案，你们想听听我的
pitch all right here's my political
方案吗？好的，这就是我的政治
pitch right nuclear submarines have been
方案。核潜艇已经进行了
testing this for 50 years they're
50年的测试，它们
perfectly safe right people going to
绝对安全，对吧？人们可以
live in a nuclear sub next to the
住在核潜艇里，就在
reactor they're fine right so we build
反应堆旁边，他们没问题，对吧？所以我们建造
one of those there's no not in my
一个这样的潜艇，不，不是建在我家
backyard we put it in everyone's
后院，而是建在每个人的
backyard there's a nuclear reactor like
后院。每个城市都应该有一个核反应堆，就像
a submarine in every city bury it have a
潜艇一样，把它埋在地下，
small power unit in every city City and
每个城市、城镇都应该有一个小型发电装置。 现在能源
expensive so you pay your fuel Bill and
价格很高，所以你得支付燃料费。
in 20 years time we don't worry about
20年后，我们不用担心
cop 23 we we burn all the fossil fuels
COP23，我们可以想烧多少化石燃料就烧多少，
we want for 20 years and then in one day
然后一夜之间，
we go totally green right no more fossil
我们就彻底绿色化，对吧？不再需要化石
fuels well a little bit for fertilizers
燃料了，好吧，可能还会用一点做化肥
and stuff but no more essentially and
之类的，但基本上不用了。
then fuel over the next 10 years uh
接下来的10年，
Power becomes
能源将
free so we say to businesses around the
免费。所以我们会告诉世界各地的企业，
world you want to set up a business in
你们想在
Britain it's quite expensive to employ
英国创业吗？雇佣
people but Energy's free you think we
员工成本很高，但能源是免费的。你们觉得我们
live in a world where energy will be of
生活在一个20年后能源仍然有价值的世界吗？
time is it going to be the thing yes so
会的。所以
you say to your Amazon and your Googles
你会问亚马逊和谷歌，
do you want to set up the place here
你们想在这里设立办事处吗？当然想！
great if I rule the world that's what I
如果我统治世界，我就会这么做。
would do Trump's probably going to come
特朗普很可能会
back into Power isn't he by the looks of
再次掌权，不是吗？从目前的情况来看，
things Biden's not doesn't seem to be
拜登似乎
very compelling to people according to
对人们没什么吸引力。根据
some of the polls I mean a week is a
一些民调，我的意思是，
long time in politics who knows who
在政治中，一周的时间很长，谁
knows what will happen I think America
知道会发生什么呢？我认为
will be fine regardless America is um
无论如何，美国都会没事的。美国…… 从
Geographic rically economically uh it's
地理位置和经济角度来看，美国是
a net exporter of fuel and of food it's
燃料和食品的净出口国，它
got incredible Neighbors in Canada and
拥有加拿大和墨西哥这样强大的邻国。
incredible 20 years regardless of who
无论谁上台，美国都将在未来20年迎来前所未有的发展，
gets in they're going to double their
其
industrial base in the next 20 years
工业基础将在未来20年内翻一番，
because everything that was globalized
因为所有曾经全球化的事物都
is becoming more insula uh which isn't
变得更加封闭。这
necessarily good for the world but very
对世界未必是好事，但
good for America America can afford to
对美国来说却是天赐良机。美国可以承受
have a terrible political system because
糟糕的政治体制，因为
it is so blessed
它如此幸运。它将在
they're going to own much of the AI race
人工智能领域占据主导地位，
as well all the big AI companies seem to
所有大型人工智能公司似乎都
be based in America and that feel feels
位于美国。这感觉就像……
like that's going to really I'm not
我并不
worried about Ai No AI is a covers band
担心人工智能。人工智能就像一支翻唱乐队，
it's it's artificial intelligence it's
它是人工智能，而
not artificial Consciousness right so if
不是人工意识。所以，如果
you tell it to write a joke it can spit
你让它写个笑话，它可能会把
back stuff that you've already written
你已经写好的东西重新排列一下，
and reorder it slightly but yeah don't
但不用
worry about it but if you imagine the
担心。想象一下，
Beatles aren't worried about the bootleg
披头士乐队并不担心盗版
Beatles but if you imagine at sort of
披头士乐队，但想象一下，即使盗版
even a 20% rate of improvement every
率达到20%…… 每年都有进步，
you know that compounds it's only going
你知道，这只会让情况变得更糟。
to take us five or 10 years before
再过五到十年，就会出现
there's a [__] AI that can crack a
一个他妈的AI，它能讲出一个
joke really really [__] well great
真正他妈的棒极了的笑话，
and and an original
而且还是原创的
joke I don't know whether it's going to
笑话。我不知道它是不是真的
be original I think there is something
原创，我觉得这其中有些东西……
about I mean uh you know I don't know
你知道，“
genius is an over overused term right so
天才”这个词已经被用滥了，对吧？所以，
Genius right there's there's um there's
天才有两种类型，对吧？一种是
innate actual genius there's you know
与生俱来的真正天才，你知道，像
bark or bethoven or whatever you know
巴克、贝多芬之类的，你知道，
genius genius and then there's um hyper
天才；另一种是……超速理性，就是
know people talk about comic genius and
人们常说的喜剧天才，
they go that's what they're talking
他们说的就是
about hyper accelerated rationality and
超速理性。
I think AI is a long way from either of
我觉得AI离这两种都还很远，离
something that's genuinely
真正
original no it's a covers band it can it
原创的东西还差得远呢。不，它就像一个翻唱乐队，它可以……它可以……它可以……它可以……
it can it can go well that's the genre
好吧，这就是类型，
and I can do something that's a bit
我可以做一些
similar but there's something about
类似的东西，但
human creativity that I don't think it's
人类的创造力中有些东西，我觉得AI还没有掌握。
and maybe I'm being naive but I think
也许我有点天真，但我认为这对
world because I think new jobs will come
世界来说将是一件了不起的事情，因为我认为新的工作机会将会出现。
along this wasn't a job 10 years ago
十年前，这还不是一份工作，对吧？
right being a podcaster you tell someone
做播客，你跟别人说你要做一个很
a long radio show but people but it's an
长的广播节目，但人们会觉得这是
individual you'd have to explain it you
个人工作，你得解释清楚。你
know it things change and it's only when
知道，事物在变化，只有当
you sort of look back you go oh wow
你回顾过去时，你才会惊叹：“哇，真
that's interesting the biggest TV
有意思！世界上最大的电视
channel in the world is YouTube
频道是YouTube，
and no one noticed the BBC were battling
没人注意到BBC和
with ITV about who's going to get the
ITV还在争夺
higher ratings on a Saturday night and
周六晚上的收视率，而
YouTube stole their lunch because they
YouTube抢走了他们的饭碗，因为他们根本
weren't paying
没
attention is that not AI well it's the
注意到。”这难道不是人工智能的体现吗？
world it's the world progresses and
这就是世界，世界在进步，
things move on and it's always been fine
事物在发展，一直以来都很好。
I think people worrying about AI it
我觉得人们对人工智能的担忧让
really strikes me it's the people going
我很惊讶，他们说：“
well these we've got to smash up these
我们必须砸碎
these cotton making machines because
这些棉花生产机器，因为
this is this is this can't happen
这个、这个、这个不能再发生了，
there'll be no new jobs they'll just be
不会有新的工作，只是工作形式
different jobs I read a book called The
不同而已。” 我读过一本书叫《
innovators dilemma and it really changed
创新者的窘境》，它真的改变了
my mind on a few things they go back
我的一些想法。这本书回顾了
through history and they look at all of
历史，分析了所有
the big steps forward in Innovation and
重大的创新举措，并将
innovation I'll call it the upward
创新大致分为两类，我称之为向上
opportunity and the downward opportunity
机会和向下机会。
so if you're selling horses back in the
假设你在
1880s the upward opportunity is the
19世纪80年代卖马，那么向上机会就是所有
thing that all your customers are asking
客户都在要求的
for it is the thing that you know how to
东西，是你知道如何
do it is the thing that you have your
做的东西，也是你的
supply chain setup to deliver on which
供应链能够提供的，比如
is faster and better horses you know you
更快更好的马。你
can imagine the meeting that you're the
可以想象一下这样的会议：你是
CEO of horse company I come in I go
马业公司的CEO，我走进​​会议室，说：“
listen boss got an idea they go what is
老板，我有个想法。”他们问：“什么想法？”我说：“
it I go faster horses you go people
更快的马。”他们说：“人们都在要求。”我说：“是
asking for it I go yeah do we know how
啊，我们知道怎么
to do it yeah um do we have a customer B
做吗？嗯，我们有客户吗？”B：是的，那就
yeah let's do that then then another guy
做吧。这时，另一个人
comes in and says Jimmy I've got an idea
进来，说：“吉米，我有个想法……
um cars are they better no you have to
汽车是不是更好？”不，你得拿着
walk in front of it with a red red flag
红旗走到车前，它才能以
and it goes 10 miles an hour do we know
每小时10英里的速度行驶。我们知道
how to do it no is anyone asking for it
怎么做吗？不知道。有人要求吗？
no one none of our customers have asked
没有人，我们的客户中没有人要求过我们做
for a horse yeah that is the downward
播客，是的，这就是向下发展的
opportunity and throughout history the
机会。纵观历史，
incumbents always ignore the downward
现有企业总是忽略向下发展的
opportunity because their incentives as
机会，因为正如
you said their incentives are set up to
你所说，他们的激励机制是为了
pursue what we call the sustaining
追求我们所说的持续性
Innovation the obvious thing in front of
创新，也就是摆在他们面前的显而易见的事情：
them become a better comedian or become
成为更优秀的喜剧演员或
a better podcaster get another camera
播客主播，再添置一台摄像机。
the downward opportunity I asked myself
向下发展的机会是什么？我问自己，播客的
what is the downward opportunity in
向下发展的机会是什么？
podcasting L you should ask uh you
你
should ask comedians comedians got an
应该问问喜剧演员，喜剧演员的
interesting way of thinking I think
思维方式很有趣。我认为
we're very similar to
我们和
detectives because we think backwards
侦探很像，因为我们是逆向思考的。
most people think about what's next
大多数人思考的是下一步，对吧？也就是
right which is what you're talking about
你刚才说的，下一步是什么？下一步是什么？下一步是什么？然后
thing what's the next thing and we go
我们会想，好吧，
well this is the state of affairs how
这就是现状，
did this happen it's the same as it's
这是怎么发生的？这就像
like being Sherlock Holmes you go how
夏洛克·福尔摩斯一样，你会想，这到底是怎么回事？
you're reverse engineering a lot of the
你很多时候都在进行逆向工程。
time it's very interesting that this is
这很有意思，
this may yet be a business
这可能最终会成为一个商业
podcast I think I I honestly think with
播客。我真的认为，只要投入
the right amount of work if you really
足够的精力，如果你真的
put yourself into this I genuinely think
投入其中。 把自己融入进来，我真心觉得
you can occasionally talk about
你可以偶尔聊聊
business I tried to I try and weave it
生意，我试着把它穿插
in where I can yeah but that's
进去，是的，但
interesting that the the podcast thing
播客这件事很有意思，
of going no one saw podcast coming
没人预料到播客的出现，没人想到过
nobody like this and yet what's missing
这种形式，然而
from our lives right what's what's
我们的生活中到底缺少什么？到底
missing what's the nature of BS of
缺少什么？空虚的本质是什么？
vacuum well people aren't having
人们不再
conversations people are when you look
交流了。看看
around the world all those people that
世界各地，那些
live to 100 all of those zones and
活到100岁的人，那些长寿的人，
people go oh yeah they eat loads of
人们会说，哦，他们吃很多
olive oil and fish maybe that's the
橄榄油和鱼，也许这就是
answer no it isn't they eat with other
答案。不，不是的。他们和别人一起吃饭，
people they have a conversation they're
他们交流，他们是
part of a community that's the
社群的一份子，这就是
difference they've got something to live
区别。他们有活着的意义，
for the olive oil isn't making any
橄榄油根本无关紧要。
[__] difference the connection to
与
other human beings is what are you doing
他人的联系才是关键。你在这里做什么？
here you're connecting to people you're
你在与人交流，你在
having a conversation so people are
对话。所以人们在
eavesdropping on a conversation but in
偷听别人的对话，但在
their heads they're having a
他们自己的脑海里，他们也在进行
conversation and they're the stuff we're
对话，他们
talking about they're relating to their
谈论的正是他们自己的
lives great nobody was asking for this
生活。很棒，虽然没人要求过这个，也没人
though nobody was saying do you know
说过“你……” 我知道
what I want three hours of Jimmy Carr
我想要三个小时的吉米·卡尔
talking about life no one was like
谈人生，没人会
demanding that in the like B someone you
要求这个，你
know someone roll rolling their eyes as
知道，有些人
they listen to this yeah and I'm turning
听着会翻白眼，然后我就
off now but in that industry they
关掉了。但在这个行业里，他们
probably thought people want bigger TVs
可能觉得人们想要更大
and thinner TVs that's what they want
更薄的电视，
they want to watch the BBC on a thinner
他们想要在更薄
bigger television so we're going to
更大的电视上看BBC，所以我们要
deliver it to them whereas the the down
满足他们的需求。然而，
opportunity was in fact they wanted
他们真正想要的是
connection they wanted it to be longer
互动，他们想要更长的节目，他们
form they didn't want loads of ads every
不想每六秒钟就插播一堆广告。
great sort of if you're listening to
如果你正在听
this and you're thinking right what am I
这个节目，心想“我该怎么
going to do it's like it's not like
办？”，这难道不是个好主意吗？好像没
someone has spotted the Gap in the
人发现了市场上的空白，而
market you could be the person you know
你就是那个人，你知道，就是
and it's it's that thing of like do what
那种“做你自己，
you do authentically um I I always think
真实地做自己”的感觉。我一直觉得
like Joe Rogan's a really interesting
乔·罗根就是一个很好的
example of that of someone that's
例子，他
entirely authentic what you talk about
完全真实，他谈论
comedy and MMA and life and slightly
喜剧、​​MMA、人生，还有一些
know philosophy stuff that he's
他
interested he's exactly the same guy he
感兴趣的哲学方面的东西。 他跟
years ago in The Comedy Store back
年前在喜剧商店
backstage chatting he's exactly that guy
后台聊天时一模一样，
totally authentic and people just yeah
完全真实，人们都说，
great I listen to that all day you're
太棒了，我整天都在听，你就是你。
exactly who you are I mean I love the
我的意思是，我喜欢
idea that you think there's still a bit
你认为你内心深处仍然觉得
of you that thinks it's a business
这是一个商业
podcast it's not it's not you re you
播客的想法，但其实不是，你只是
have a thing where you love stories and
喜欢讲故事，
you love chatting to people and you love
喜欢和人聊天，喜欢
learning and that's what it is this is
学习，这就是它的本质。
just it's the this should be called the
这应该叫《
education of Steven bartler well I the
史蒂文·巴特勒的教育》。我之所以认为这是一个
reason I think this is a business
商业
podcast is because of what I said I
播客，是因为我刚才说的，我
think business is mental like this is
认为商业是精神层面的。这节目
called The Diary of a CEO right what
叫《CEO日记》，对吧？
would you find in the Diary of a CEO you
你在《CEO日记》里会找到什么？你
wouldn't find [__] forecasts and pnls
不会找到什么该死的预测和损益表，对吧？
would you you'd find problems with his
你会发现他和
wife and you'd find that he's having anx
妻子之间的问题，你会发现他焦虑
xiety attacks and you'd find that he's
发作，你会发现他根本
doesn't know what the [__] he's doing so
不知道自己在干什么。所以，
the whole point of this was to go into
这节目的全部意义在于…… 要深入了解
the Diary of a CEO the things you that's
CEO的日记，你会发现，除了
not business that's the rest of his life
生意之外，还有他生活的其他方面。
this is about life I mean I I love it I
这关乎生活，我的意思是，我非常喜欢它，真的非常
absolutely love it I'm not breaking your
喜欢。我不是在故意刁难你，
balls but it's like it's it's uh it's
但
it's great the way that it's kind of
它的发展方式真的很棒。
developed I think yeah it's been led by
我认为，
as you say curiosity I get people all
正如你所说，好奇心引领着它。我
the time will say Steve we want the
经常听到有人说：“史蒂夫，我们想要那些
[__] CEOs back we want to listen to
该死的CEO回来，我们想听听
the business people or whatever and I
商人的意见”之类的，而我只会说：“
just go you know I can't do that for a
你知道，我不可能
decade what I can do for a decade is
十年都这么做。我能做的十年是
follow my curiosity like I could do that
追随我的好奇心，就像我可以在
for the next 30 40 years and at some
接下来的三四十年里一直这样做一样。
point I'm going to care about a zmek and
总有一天，我会对迷幻药感兴趣，就像
I cared about psychedelics and so that's
我曾经对迷幻药感兴趣一样，所以这就是
what I'm going to talk about and if you
我要谈论的内容。如果你
don't like it then there are three other
不喜欢，那还有三百
million other options yeah I think that
万种其他选择。”是的，我认为
thing about that's going with your gut
跟随你的直觉
is going to be the way to go because if
才是正道，因为如果
you like the show and if you're having
你喜欢这个节目，如果你
interest in conversations I think the
感兴趣，那就去做吧。 在对话中，我觉得
listener will will go with that and if
听者会顺着你的意思走。如果
you try and give them what they wanted I
你试图满足他们的需求，我
think it's the it's exactly that thing
觉得就像是，他们说
of going we need Better Faster Horses
我们需要的是更好更快的马，而
not a car and you're going well you need
不是一辆车，而你却说，好吧，你们需要
a car cuz whatever this is in 10 years
一辆车，因为不管这是什么，十年后都会不
time it's going to be different right
一样，对吧？
it's going be it'll be something I'll
它会变成我当
dad and I'll be thinking about a
爸爸时会思考的
different set of problems and I'll be
另一套问题，我会和
speaking to parental psychologists about
育儿心理学家讨论我该
what F do with my kids and stuff yeah um
如何对待我的孩子等等。嗯，
but Rogan was the blue I have to say it
但罗根（Rogan）确实很棒，我必须说，
and I think I've dm'd him it I don't
我想我给他发过私信，虽然
think he replied but I just said to him
他没有回复，但我有一天告诉他，
one day that the blueprint he said about
他关于保持
authenticity and following whatever it
真实和追随
is you're interested in has helped me so
自己兴趣的理念对我的帮助非常
much because is there's more pressure to
大，因为
change when there's more people watching
当更多的人关注你时，改变的压力也会更大。
and they can I've seen petitions and
我看到过请愿书，也
I've seen little movements on LinkedIn
看到过LinkedIn上的一些小活动，
trying to get me to have more of these
试图让我邀请更多这样的
kind of people on the single biggest
人来做这件事。这是
request I have on this podcast is to
我对此最大的请求。 播客的目的是
quote interview normal people that are
采访那些正处于
at the start of their Journey that's the
人生旅程起点的普通人，这是
quote that's what they say to me um and
他们跟我说的话。嗯，
I go well if you'd interviewed Stephen
我会说，如果你采访的是
18 yeah not a lot to talk about um you
18岁的斯蒂芬，那确实没什么好说的。你
know so it really be them interviewing
知道，所以实际上是他们来采访
me maybe that tends to what happens who
我，也许这种情况更常见，
would be the student in that situation
在这种情况下，谁会是学生呢？
um but it's that's the most popular
嗯，但
request I get is to go and interview
我收到的最受欢迎的请求就是去采访
quote unquote normal
所谓的“
people so yeah ignoring that I mean as
普通人”。所以，抛开这一点，我的意思是，
you must have been able had to ignore
你肯定能够忽略那些来自
the external pressure of changing or
外部的压力，比如改变风格、
telling a certain type of joke or being
讲某种类型的笑话，或者成为某种
a certain type of no I think I think I
类型的人。不，我认为，我认为，对
think the audience though for me because
我来说，观众会
tell me what they find funny and that
告诉我他们觉得什么好笑，这会让
kind of leads you down the road of going
你觉得“这很
that's that's interesting people want to
有趣，人们
hear this I think the reason people are
想听这个”。我认为人们被
drawn to my comedy is partly because
我的喜剧吸引的部分原因是，
there's not a lot of censorship in our
我们的社会审查制度并不多，但
society there's quite a lot of self
自我
censorship so people aren't speaking
审查却很多，所以人们
freely in the office or even at home
在办公室甚至其他地方都不能畅所欲言。 在家，
they're not saying what they really
他们不会说出自己的真实
think if you notice this thing opinion
想法。如果你注意到这一点，民意
polls don't seem as accurate as they
调查似乎不如
once were and that's because people
以前那么准确了。这是因为人们
don't feel like they don't vote in the
觉得他们的投票方式和他们在世界上的
same way as they as they as they express
表达方式并不相同。
so they come and see me live and there's
所以他们来看我的现场演出，没有任何
no filter and this guy's saying whatever
顾虑，这个人想说什么就说什么，这个人
he wants this guy doesn't seem to give a
似乎毫不在乎。
cathartic if you're spending your days
如果你每天都在想着“
going well I know what the right thing
我知道该
to say is so I'll say the right thing
说什么，所以我得说正确的话”，那么这会让你感觉很畅快。
you know if you want to see who has
如果你想看看谁
power in a society who can't you
在一个社会中拥有权力，谁不能
criticize and making jokes and making
批评、开玩笑、轻描淡写地看待这一切，这很有
powerful because it it uh it's about
力量，因为它关乎
free speech and it's about um the
言论自由，也关乎奥弗
Overton window you know that Overton
顿之窗。你知道，奥弗顿之窗指的是哪些话题可以谈论，
window of what is and what isn't
哪些话题不能谈论。
there's an no window in politics of what
在政治领域，存在一个“无视窗口”，用来界定哪些政策可以接受，
what is and what isn't acceptable policy
哪些政策不能接受；而
talk about in polite society and I think
在文明社会中，则存在一个“推翻窗口”，用来界定哪些话题可以谈论，哪些话题不能谈论。我认为
comedy has a really valuable role in
喜剧在改变人们的讨论范围方面发挥着非常重要的作用。
about I'm always very interested in like
我总是对这样的情况很感兴趣：
occasionally it happens where you'll
偶尔你会
overhear the audience leaving a comedy
听到观众看完喜剧
show and have such great
演出后进行一些很棒的
conversations it's really interesting
对话。这真的很有意思，
how it like just Taps into they just
就像喜剧触动了他们内心深处，让他们
feel a bit Freer and looser because
感觉更自由、更放松，因为
they've listened to someone on stage
他们听了台上那些
being very loose and they're not
非常放松、不
buttoned down they're not trying to
拘束、不
self-censor or say the right
自我审查、不试图说正确的
thing self- expression and expression
话的人的表演。自我表达，以及一般的表达方式，一直在经历着巨大的变化。
journey like you know this whole idea of
你知道，现在这种“
wokeism and what you can and can't say
觉醒主义”的概念，以及你能说什么不能说什么，
it's I mean it really accelerated in the
在过去的十年里发展得非常迅速，以至于……
it's quite you know it's quite if I look
你知道，如果我
back at comedy videos from 20 years ago
回顾20年前的喜剧视频，
they really seem to just be able to say
他们似乎真的可以畅所欲言。
then we went through this era of like
然后我们经历了
censorship and cancellation and there's
审查和取消的时代，
no time in human history where the good
在人类历史上，从来没有哪个时期
guys have censored
是正义的一方审查过任何
stuff it's never happened so wherever
东西。 这种事从未发生过，所以无论这种说法来自何方，
that's coming from whether it's the
无论是
right you know the marry White House ban
右翼，比如白宫过去禁止
this filth which used to be the case or
这种污秽言论的言论，还是
the left the idea that the there's um
左翼，比如存在
you know a hate speech or or the idea
仇恨言论，或者认为
that something could be words can be
言语可以等同于
violence um which is you know what
暴力——你知道，
people say when they've never
人们在从未
experienced real violence I guess um the
经历过真正的暴力时会这么说——我想，正是因为
there's such demand for violence we had
对暴力的需求如此之大，
to we had to co-opt words into it but
我们才不得不将言语纳入其中。但是，
the idea of going this you're trying to
试图
censor stuff is is a bad idea free
审查言论的想法是糟糕的，
speech is a very good idea because those
言论自由才是非常好的想法，因为
thoughts don't go away if people don't
如果人们不表达自己，这些想法并不会消失，它们只会遭到
get suppressed and and actually just
压制。事实上，
speaking freely about stuff and talking
自由地谈论和讨论事物是
about it is is very very valuable when
非常宝贵的，尤其是在
you're trying to build something the
你试图建立某些东西的时候。
problem that we all face is we need to
我们都面临的问题是，我们需要自己
talent and skills that we don't have
不具备的才能和技能，
ourselves and we can waste so much time
我们可能会浪费大量时间去
trying to learn a new skill when really
学习一项新技能，而我们真正
what we should be doing is using a
应该做的是使用
platform like fiverr.com where you have
像fiverr.com这样的平台，在那里你可以
Global access to reviewed tried and
接触到全球经过审核、尝试和
tested worldclass Talent at your
测试的世界级人才。
fingertips that you can access in a
Fiverr 让我能够以
flexible and affordable way fiver for me
灵活且经济实惠的方式轻松获取所需资源。
when I was starting out in business was
在我创业初期，Fiverr 对我来说
a real unlock it was a bit of a hack
简直是打开了新世界的大门。它有点像个“捷径”，
because I used to think that the only
因为我以前一直认为，为
way for me to add skills to to my
我的项目增添技能的唯一方法
project was by hiring full-time staff
就是雇佣全职员工，把
and bringing them into the office
他们带到办公室来。Fiverr.com
fiver.com changes that and if you're in
改变了这一切。如果你
that position now where there's a skill
现在也面临着
you're missing for a project that
项目技能不足的问题，那么
matters to you here's what you have to
你需要
do visit fiverr.com diary tolearn more
做的就是访问 fiverr.com 的“日记”页面了解更多信息。
and here's the great thing if it doesn't
更棒的是，如果合作不
go well Fiverr offer a pretty amazing
顺利，Fiverr 提供非常棒的
money back guarantee so what are you
退款保证。所以你还在等什么呢？
for if you were a podcaster would you
如果你是一位播客主播，你会邀请
have anyone on the podcast would there
任何人上你的播客吗？
be any limits you would set that's
你会设定什么限制吗？
something I think about a lot where are
我经常思考这个问题：
my limits because I get a lot of
我的底线在哪里？因为我经常收到这样的
messages saying would you have this
信息：你会邀请这个
person on would you speak to Trump would
人上节目吗？你会和特朗普对话吗？
you speak to Vladimir Putin would you
你会和普京
speak to you know yeah I mean I think I
对话吗？你知道，我的意思是，我
think you're I think you have to speak
认为你应该和
to everyone I think the idea of going
所有人对话。我认为，应该去和所有人对话。 有些
beyond the pale people have got like
人的想法简直离谱，就像有些人脑子里全是
there's people with bad ideas right I
坏想法一样。我
don't know if there's that many bad
不知道坏人是不是真的很多，
people but there's bad incentives and
但肯定有不良动机，而且
people that follow them and talking to
有人会追随这些动机。
everyone seems incredibly valuable to me
我觉得和每个人都交流非常有价值，
and the idea that you go yeah that's how
而且这种想法本身就很有道理：
life moves forward you know there's you
生活就是这样向前发展的。你
know even you want to be a Marxist it's
知道，即使你想成为一个马克思主义者，这也是一种
a dialectic of going well this person I
辩证法，你会说，这个人我
don't agree with and you have the
不同意他的观点，但你要和他进行
conversation and with an open mind and
对话，保持开放的心态和
an open heart and maybe you change their
真诚的心，也许你能改变他的
mind and how do you move the
想法。那么，你该如何推动
conversation forward I mean the great
对话向前发展呢？
mystery for me in politics is the idea
对我来说，政治中最大的谜团就是
that people talk about um Hypocrites in
人们谈论
politics changing their mind about
政治伪君子改变主意这件事。
things of course he changed his mind the
当然，他改变了主意，
facts have changed that the world's
事实改变了，世界也
changed you move
改变了，所以要
on Obama ran on an anti-gay marriage
向前看。奥巴马竞选时反对同性婚姻，
but the world moves on and things
但世界在发展，事物在
progress and you know I'm I'm you know a
进步。你知道，我是一个
progressive but I think the idea of not
进步人士，但我认为不
listening to people is poison you know
倾听他人的想法是有害的。
you think about why Hillary lost the
想想希拉里为什么输掉了
election right it was that deplorables
选举，对吧？就是因为“可悲之人”那
thing remember when she talked about the
件事。还记得她谈到……的时候吗？
deplorables and you can't talk to those
你不能把他们当成“可悲之人”，也不能跟他们说话。但事实并非如此，他们只是普通的
those are just working class people and
工人阶级，
they've got they've got worries and you
他们也有自己的烦恼，你
need to talk to them about those worries
需要和他们谈谈这些烦恼。
you can't just write them all off and go
你不能把他们都排除在外，说
well they're despicable people you know
他们是卑鄙的人，你知道
that Urban Elite kind of thing you've
那种“城市精英”的思维。你
got to bring them in have the
必须把他们拉进来，和他们
conversation you'll get someone with it
对话，你会找到理解他们的人。
you you know you have to listen to that
你必须倾听，
you have to listen to all the different
你必须倾听
sides of the argument otherwise we're
争论的各个方面，否则我们就会
entrenched we're just in these little
固步自封，困在这些狭小的空间里。
you know and it's it's that thing of
你知道，这就像身份
like it becomes uh identity you know
认同一样，你知道，
which party that you follow crazy people
你追随哪个党派。疯狂的人
don't like to follow people that they
不喜欢追随那些在网上和他们意见相左的人，
because that's creating cognitive
因为这会造成认知
dissonance isn't it it's a constant
失调，不是吗？这会不断地让你面对
confrontation of a set of ideas that
一系列
threaten or challenge you in some way so
威胁或挑战你的观点，所以
we'd rather just create this little Echo
我们宁愿创建一个小小的回音
chamber of individuals that will confirm
室，里面的人会证实
my set my set of existing beliefs and
我既有的信念。
that's what you know one of the things I
这就是
I made the decision to do about two
我做出这个决定的原因之一。 大概
three years ago was just to follow
两三年前，我做的就是关注
everyone that I am viscerally sort of
那些我本能地
repulsed by should I say yeah and if you
反感的人，应该说，是的，如果你
had them on the show if you had people
邀请他们上节目，如果你邀请那些你
on the show that you go I don't really
不太认同他们观点的人上节目，是的，是的，
it's I I feel like great to be back
我感觉很高兴能回来，是的，嗯，
yeah the uh that's interesting I think
这很有意思，
that's really I think that's really
我认为这真的很有
valuable I think that's a more
价值，我认为这会引发更
interesting conversation as well because
有趣的对话，因为
if you're just going to nod along with
如果你只是点头附和
someone and go well it's talking sense
别人，说“嗯，说得有道理，
that's great it's like you know and it I
很好”，那就没什么意义了。我
think to have those kind of difficult
认为进行这种艰难的
conversations is really it's a valuable
对话真的很有价值。
thing one thing you said which surprised
你刚才说的一件事让
me because it didn't come at all up at
我很惊讶，因为在
all in our previous conversation at all
我们之前的谈话中，
and even in my prior research was you
甚至在我之前的调查中，你完全没有提到过。你
said that you feel like you have a
说你觉得自己有
lowlevel eating
轻微的饮食
disorder yeah I think I'm very uh very
障碍，是的，我想我非常非常
conscious of my uh weight and my
在意我的体重和
appearance and I think that's
外表，我想这
maybe uh Eating Disorders are very
可能是……饮食障碍是非常非常
they're very very serious things and I'm
严重的问题。 我其实
not um I'm not really in that category
不属于那个范畴，
but I'm very aware of it like as a as a
但我作为一个男人，对此非常清楚。
man as well I was chatting to um Chris
我之前在
Williamson on about this on uh modern
Modern Wisdom节目上和Chris Williamson聊过这个，
wisdom I think I think he was like
他好像
quoting the stat of saying men's uh body
引用了一个数据，说男性的体像
morphia overtakes women's I think in the
障碍症会超过女性。我觉得
next year in terms of kind of young men
明年会有更多年轻男性在
looking at Instagram wanting to look a
Instagram上追求某种
certain way and presenting themselves a
特定的外貌和形象，这确实会成为一个
of an issue around it I think that weird
问题。我觉得这很奇怪，
thing about like I've had a bit of work
就像我做了一些整容手术，比如整
done you know and had my teeth done and
牙、
my hair done and I think there is kind
做头发等等。我觉得
screen all the time that you get very
长时间出现在屏幕上会让你格外
conscious of kind of uh and maybe it's
在意自己的形象，也许这有点像是一种
slightly a control thing have you always
控制欲。你一直都有
had that um or is it developed I think
这种感觉吗？还是后来才形成的？我觉得
it's kind I think it's slightly
这有点像是后天
developed through sort of you know I
形成的。我
think if I wasn't on TV or on Netflix or
想，如果我不上电视、不上Netflix之类的平台，我
whatever I think you probably wouldn't
可能不会那么
be as aware of how you how you present
在意自己的形象。 你展现
yourself um so it's it's slightly odd
自己的方式，嗯，这有点奇怪，就像……
like thing slightly odd relationship
有点奇怪的关系，
with I mean I I have kind of a theory
我的意思是，我对
around um around drugs right drugs and
毒品，对吧，毒品和
alcohol so I think marijuana when you
酒精，有一些理论。所以我觉得，当你
think about it like weed
想到大麻，比如weed，
uh is people are very Carefree about H
人们对它非常随意，
well that's just a bit of weed fine but
好吧，那只是一点点weed，没问题，但
think about what it is right it's not an
想想它是什么，对吧？它不是一种
performance-enhancing drug it's a
兴奋剂，而是一种
performance inhibiting drug right it
抑制剂，对吧？它会
takes away your ambition and agency and
剥夺你的雄心和自主性，只会让
it just makes you very chilled and
你变得非常放松和
relaxed and I don't think that's
慵懒，我认为这对
appropriate for men in their 20s or
20多岁的男性或十几岁的
teenagers right actually what you want
青少年来说并不合适，对吧？实际上，你想要的
is the performance and arting and I
是表演和艺术，我
think what we should be s promoting is
认为我们应该提倡的
almost like prohibition I mean I did it
几乎是禁酒令。我的意思是，我做这一切的过程有点
kind of organically I found comedy and I
自然，我发现了喜剧，然后我
gave up drinking for 12 years I didn't
戒酒了12年，
touch a drop and that was mainly because
一滴都没碰过，这主要是因为
of Lifestyle because I was driving to
生活方式，因为我要开车去
gigs and driving back and then I didn't
演出，开车 回去之后，我不想
want to hang over the next day because I
第二天宿醉，因为我真的
I wanted to and everyone was trying to
很想宿醉，而且每个人都想
buy you drinks all the time and it just
请我喝酒，
felt like it was like enough already I'm
感觉已经够了，我要戒酒，
going to be I'm going to be straight
我要成为“直
edge which I always like the term
刃族”（straight edge），我一直很喜欢“
straight edge it's a punk rock term for
直刃族”这个词，它是朋克摇滚的说法，意思是完全的“
being T tootal straight edge it's cooler
直刃”，听起来很酷，对吧？嗯，
mhm but I like the idea of going right
我喜欢这种“戒酒”的想法，
I'm going to control that I mean I drink
我要控制自己。我的意思是，我
a little bit now kind of socially but uh
现在偶尔会喝点酒，算是社交场合，但
not in a problem way but giving up was
不是那种酗酒。戒酒对我来说
quite an important
很重要，
thing because it was also the focus that
因为它能让你更加专注。
it gives you so I don't know I I kind of
所以，我不知道，我有点……有点反对
young people I slightly think men in
年轻人吸毒。我觉得
their 50s and 60s that that are
五六十岁的
Workaholics maybe some marijuana
工作狂男人，也许吸点大麻也不错。
idea but it's the it's the idea of kind
但问题是，
of young people taking it and not having
年轻人吸毒，而不是真正地吸毒，它会夺走你什么？它会扼杀你
takes away that kind of that that raw
那种原始的
ambition and that's as such a sort of
雄心壮志。
valuable thing in those years it's
在那些年里，这几乎是一种宝贵的财富，就像
people can't see the advantage that they
年轻人看不到的优势一样。
have they see the the the the wealth uh
他们只看到50岁时的财富
and the you know the financial um
和经济
security of being 50 and when you're 20
保障，而20岁时，
what you don't recognize is the energy
你意识不到自己拥有的活力。20岁时，
that you have when you're 20 that Inc
你拥有着一种
inredible Advantage you have over
不可思议的优势，比
everyone else in the office in that
办公室里的其他人都更有优势，因为你
just you're just full of energy your 20
精力充沛。你
years older than me exactly what advice
比我大20岁，
would you give to me that's unobvious as
你会给我什么建议？作为
a 31 year old you're 51 I believe yeah
一个31岁的人，你会给我什么建议？这些建议可能不太明显。你51岁了，对吧？
at my age about the next sort of 20
关于我接下来20
years of my life stay out the
年的生活，你会给我什么建议？尽量避免
sun stay out the sun sun damage is is
阳光暴晒。阳光损伤占衰老的
90% of Aging stay out the sun honestly
90%。说实话，尽量避免阳光暴晒，
you'll save a fortune plastic
你会省下一大笔整形
surgeon uh the uh I don't know I mean I
费用。呃，我不知道，我的意思是，我觉得
think that you know I don't know if you
你现在的情况可能比现在
could be in a better place right now
更好。
than you are but you can certainly give
比你现在的年纪要大，但
yourself gifts when you're 50 what gifts
你50岁的时候当然可以给自己买礼物。
do you want to give yourself let's talk
你想给自己买什么礼物呢？我们来聊聊
receive on your 51st birthday from
你51岁生日时想收到自己送的什么礼物吧。很
you interesting what would you like to
有意思，你想要什么？
have I'd like to be physically fit so
我想要身体健康，没问题，
done no problem at all you will need to
没问题。你需要
go to the gym three times a week and 80%
每周去健身房三次，80%的功夫
of it is going to be diet not exercise
在于饮食，而不是运动。
okay so you're going to need to do that
好的，你需要这样做，
but no problem at all I'm the genie you
但没问题，我是你的阿拉丁神灯，你明白的。
got it what else would you like I would
你还想要什么？我
like a happy healthy family and
想要一个幸福健康的家庭，和
relationship with my partner I'd like to
我的伴侣保持良好的关系。我想
be married and I'd like her to be happy
结婚，我希望她幸福，
and I'd like my kids to be happy
我希望我的孩子们幸福。好的，太好了。
okay that's great I don't think you get
我不认为你可以
to call that
把这叫做“幸福”，
I think you get to be happy and you're
我认为你应该让自己幸福，而且你
in charge of that and their happiness is
掌控着自己的幸福，他们的幸福
maybe a byproduct of that but you need I
或许是你的副产品。但你需要……
I my perception would be you need the
我的看法是，你需要把
locus of control to be within you you
控制权掌握在自己手中。你
could be happy make yourself happy and
可以让自己幸福，
that's good for the people around you
这对你周围的人也有好处。
but I don't think someone else's
但我认为，没有人会…… 别人的
happiness can be your
幸福可能是你的
responsibility you can set up all the
责任，你可以设定所有
conditions and you can you can make it
条件，你可以尽可能地简化一切，
but you know that's that's that's a lot
但你知道，这工作量很大，
but but I get the idea of it the
但我明白你的意思。
how many kids four four Jesus Christ all
四个孩子？我的天哪！
right so four four kids so you're you're
好吧，四个孩子，你已经要开
in minivan territory already you can't
面包车了，
even drive a regular car this is crazy
连普通轿车都开不了，这太疯狂了，简直疯了。
madness um four kids so one of each one
四个孩子，一男一女，没错，这就是
of each yeah a modern
现代
world uh I love that all right what else
社会。我喜欢这样。好吧，
would you what else would you want in 20
你20年后还想要什么？
years time I'd like to still be doing a
我希望还能继续做
business podcast you're not doing a
商业播客。你现在没做
business podcast now very little
商业播客，
business in this no one ever talks about
这方面商业内容很少，没人谈论
supply and demand
供需关系之类的
nonsense um I think yeah the the that
废话。嗯，我想，那种
stoic thing of like you still doing this
坚忍的想法，就像你20年后还在做这件事，那将是一段多么精彩的
in 20 years time what a journey that
旅程啊！
be like think about the people that you
想想你
will speak to think about the things
会和哪些人交流，想想
that you will learn think about the the
你会学到什么，想想
road that you're on and and actually if
你正在走的路。实际上，如果
you're open to speaking to everyone then
你愿意和每个人交流，那么
the Comm the lines of communication are
沟通渠道就能
kept open and that's incredibly
保持畅通。 开放的心态
important in the modern world where
在当今世界极其重要，因为
people are uh uh uh in these you know
人们往往被划分成
divided camps it's
不同的阵营。在
for you when you turned
你
50 that you either had or hadn't given
50岁生日那天，
yourself when you turned 50 you know you
你会环顾四周，想想
about the gifts that you either have or
你拥有或
that you wish you had what are those
渴望拥有的礼物是什么。
things I was in Australia last year on
去年我在澳大利亚
tour and
巡演，
I fairly arbitrarily I mean I was always
我当时的想法很随意——我一直很
very good at trying new material and
擅长尝试新段子，也喜欢
doing sort of warm-up gigs and I just
做一些暖场演出——我当时就想，
went oh I'm going to try something new
我要尝试一些新的东西，我要在
I'm going to do new [__] at at every
每场
show I'm going to try I'm going to write
演出中都表演一些新的东西。我要在白天写段子，
jokes during the day and then I'll try
然后在
them that night at every single
晚上每场
show and a year later I've got a new
演出中都尝试一下。一年后，我创作出了一个新的
show and it was so easy to put together
节目。这个节目很容易就完成了，
because it was just like every night
因为每晚
you're you're you're trying new new new
你都在尝试新的、新的、新的，
new and it forces you into that space of
这迫使你不断地
writing more and more more and more and
创作，
I feel like I'm getting better you know
我觉得…… 你知道，
a year on you go that was yeah that was
一年过去了，我的情况正在好转。是的，那很
that was easy and it was just little and
容易，而且往往只是些小事。
routines you know the small things
你知道，这些日常习惯，这些小事，到底有多重要？
because I think there's kind of two
因为我觉得
camps of people typically there's those
人们通常分为两派：一派
that think sweating the small stuff
认为在小事上斤斤计较很重要，另一派则
matters and there's those that think
认为在小事上斤斤计较
inconsequential and it's you know but it
无关紧要。你知道，但
seems that you know the people that I
似乎我身边那些
seem to sit here with that are really
真正
successful at what they do have a real
成功的人，都对细节有着一种近乎
obsession with the detail I remember I
痴迷的执着。我记得，我
don't know if it's the small stuff I
不知道是不是小事，但我
think it's the important stuff
认为是重要的事情。
so I wouldn't swear anything other than
所以，除了
the joke writing and the performing on
写段子和舞台表演之外，
stage everything else it's all small
其他一切都无关紧要，都是些小事，而这些才是
stuff that's the important stuff and
重要的事情。
focusing on that like knowing what's
专注于此，知道什么才是
important I guess would be the first
重要的，我想这应该是第一步。然后，是的，这
seems absolutely critical remember I sat
似乎绝对至关重要。记得我和
here with Walter isacon who followed
沃尔特·伊萨肯坐在一起，他曾跟随
Elon Musk for two years and followed
埃隆·马斯克两年，也曾跟随
Steve Jobs for two years before Steve
史蒂夫·乔布斯两年，直到乔布斯
Jobs died um both two business people
去世。他们都是商人，
he's not connected though no one thinks
虽然他们之间没有联系，但没人认为他们之间有什么联系。
it's his
是他的
fault no you're not you're not casting
错吗？不，不是的，你没有指责
any no no I'm not saying he did I'm not
任何人。不不，我不是说他做了什么，我不是
saying he did but he said something to
说他做了什么，但他跟
me about how Steve Jobs would even make
我说过，史蒂夫·乔布斯甚至会把
the circuit board inside the iPhone look
iPhone内部的电路板都做得非常
beautiful and this came from Steve Jobs
漂亮。这话出自乔布斯的
father who who told him that he had to
父亲，他父亲告诉他，
paint the back of the fence as well even
即使
though no one would ever see the back of
没人会看到
the fence because it was covered but he
围栏的背面，他也必须把背面也粉刷一遍，因为围栏是被遮挡的。他
said that truly great individuals care
说，真正伟大的人
equally about the parts that are unseen
同样关心那些看不见的部分，
you know the things you'll never see and
你知道，那些你永远不会看到的东西。
I always that's incredible that Steve
我一直觉得，史蒂夫·
Jobs would care so much about making the
乔布斯如此在意
the circuit board inside this iPhone
iPhone内部电路板的
look beautiful
美观，这真是太不可思议了。
and why is he doing that well is he
他为什么要这么做呢？
doing that because he will know you know
因为他知道……你知道，
and I and that made me think about this
这让我想到了“
concept of your self story we have you
自我故事”这个概念。你
said reputation earlier which is the
之前提到过声誉，也就是
external story of what people think of
人们对
self story about who I like when you
你的看法，但我们所做的一切都在书写着关于“我是谁”的自我故事。
leave I I love this concept the idea
我喜欢这个概念，
that we are a story We Tell ourselves
我们是一个故事，我们讲述给自己。是的，
yeah and everything I'm doing is telling
我所做的一切都在告诉
me who I am so Chris Eubank Jr the the
我我是谁。所以，克里斯·尤班克二世，……
son of the famous boxer Great boxer
的儿子 这位著名的拳击手，伟大的拳击手
himself says that he if he's on a
本人说过，如果他在
treadmill and he gets cramp in his leg
跑步机上，腿抽筋了，那种
like really painful cramp in his leg no
非常剧烈的抽筋，
one's in the gym but he told himself he
健身房里也没人，但他告诉自己
was going to do 20 km he says I I will
要跑20公里，他说：“我会一瘸一拐
physically limp the last 8K yeah even
地跑完最后8公里。”是的，即使
though no one's there of course why of
周围一个人也没有。当然，为什么？当然，
course because you you are who you who
因为你就是你，你就是你，你就是你自己，就是这样，
you who you are like that's that how you
你
do anything is how you do
做任何事的方式就是你做
everything so he's all in he's he's that
一切事的方式。所以他全力以赴，他就是那样的
guy great that's it's great that's a
人，太棒了，这很棒，这是一个
good that's a great story because you go
很好的故事，因为你会想，是的，当然，
yes well of course of course if you say
如果你说
you're going to do it and then you're
你要去做，然后你又是那种说到做到的
the kind of person that does the thing
人，
say it's powerful right if you keep a
这很强大，对吧？如果你信守
little promise to yourself that's
对自己的一个小小的承诺，这很
powerful that changes your sort of
强大，它会改变你对
perception of self you can trust
自我的认知，你会更加信任
yourself a little bit
自己。我们很多人习惯
more a lot of us pathologically let let
性地让自己失望，
ourselves down in small ways and don't
在一些小事上让自己失望，并不
really think those promises matter we
认为这些承诺很重要，我们习惯性
pathologically okay but but you can but
地违背对自己的承诺。 但是，
you can change that right you can build
你可以改变，对吧？你可以
that up a little bit and we'll see the
慢慢积累，20年后我们就能看到结果了。
and you got a family and kids and you're
你会变得健康，有家庭和孩子，而且
doing great you're still doing this it's
做得很好，你还在坚持，这
great we'll see it I think you probably
很棒，我们拭目以待。我想你可能
you can't beat yourself up over
无法事事都责备自己，对吧？
everything right you you have to choose
你必须选择在
where to suffer you have to choose
哪里承受痛苦，你必须选择对
what's the thing that matters to you and
你来说重要的事情，
don't just let yourself down on that so
不要在这方面让自己失望。所以，
maybe you're not going to do everything
也许你不可能做到所有事情，好吧，没关系。
okay fine do you think that's what
你认为这就是
confidence is confidence and yeah
自信吗？自信，是的，
confidence in yourself is just a
对自己的自信是
commitments you kept to yourself and
你对自己所作承诺的结合和最终体现，以及
what you Pro to yourself about yourself
你对自己的肯定。
I think that's uh I haven't thought
我想，嗯，我以前没这样想过，
about it like that but that seems like a
但这似乎是一个
very uh logical
非常合乎逻辑的
conclusion you know it's that thing of
结论。你知道，就是
you want to give the world irrefutable
你想给世界无可辩驳的
proof you are who you say you are well
证据，证明你就是你所说的那个人。
the world and yourself there's a mirror
世界和你自己，就像一面镜子，
up as well are you who you say you are
你是你所说的那个人吗？
yeah well great that's a that's a lovely
嗯，太好了，这真是一件美好的
thing to be and to build that up in
事情。 要一点一点地积累，
small ways I mean that's really you're
我的意思是，这其实是在
talking about building character of
培养品格，比如对
promise to myself and then I'm going to
自己许下承诺，然后说到做到。
I'm going to do it so you don't make
所以不要给
[__] promises to yourself yeah New
自己空头支票。
Year resolutions are not a good idea
新年决心不是个好主意，
because if you're going to let yourself
因为如果你让自己失望，
down that's more damaging pick something
那会更伤人。选择
that you can
你能做的事情，
do pick something
选择小事。
small last time we spoke you expressed
上次我们聊天的时候，你表达了
an aspiration an ambition you had you
一个愿望和抱负，你
said I think we were talking about Dave
说，我想我们当时在聊戴夫·
Chappelle and you said you wanted to do
查普尔，你说你想做
longer form
更长的段子。是的，
jokes yeah so there's there's some stuff
所以
in the new show so there's like 20
新节目里有一些相关内容，比如有20
minutes on being a dad um that I think
分钟是关于当爸爸的，我觉得这部分真的很
is really funny and I wanted it to fit
有趣，而且我也想让它符合
within my Persona as well because a lot
我的个人风格，因为很多
of people sort of become fathers and
人当了爸爸之后会变得
they get a bit sentimental and they lose
有点感性，失去
some of their Edge so the stuff that
一些锋芒。所以
I've got about being a father is uh is
我关于当爸爸的段子，嗯，很
brutal but it's funny it's funny it's
残酷，但也很搞笑，很有趣，这是一种很有趣的
experience as well it's something kind
体验。
of new to talk about who's your favorite
讨论你最喜欢的喜剧演员是谁，这算是个比较新的话题。
comic of all time Chris Rock really
克里斯·洛克？真的吗？
Chris Rock by yeah Chris Rock I think
克里斯·洛克？是的，克里斯·洛克。我觉得……
the uh the the I had the great pleasure
我非常荣幸能和
of working with Chris as well and he's
克里斯一起工作，他是一位
an extraordinary Talent the uh the the
非凡的天才。
he makes and the way that he sets up
他的节奏感、韵律感、观点表达方式，以及他编排段子的方式，还有
material um the way that he delivers a
他演绎台词的方式，
from sort of a technical point of view I
从技术层面来说，我都非常
admire and I love what he says I I I
欣赏他，我喜欢他说的话。我
just think he's he's he's just [__]
觉得他……他简直太他妈
hilarious and I see the work I see what
搞笑了。我看到了
he does I see the work that he does now
他的作品，看到了他现在的作品，
he's he's been a legendary Next Level
他已经是Next Level的传奇
performer for 30 years and he's still
表演者30年了，而且他仍然像以前一样
working just as
努力工作，这真的让人
hard and you got to love
敬佩。
that what did you make of this lap well
你对这次的表演有什么看法？嗯，很明显，这……毫无
argument that's it's a it's a uh I I was
疑问，这……这……我当时很
I was shocked you know it it strikes me
震惊，你知道吗？这太震撼了。 我觉得威尔·
that uh Will Smith may be the greatest
史密斯可能是他那一代最伟大的
actor of his
演员，
generation because he was pretending to
因为在过去的40年里，他一直扮演着
be an entirely different human being for
完全不同的角色，而当他的
years and The Mask
面具
slipped and we saw a a Yeah a different
滑落时，我们看到了他不为人知的一面。
side and I think Chris really the
我认为
was Chris Rock got slapped in the
克里斯·洛克在那一刻最令人惊叹的地方在于，他被人扇了一巴掌，但他却表现得异常镇定，就像
was he was like a Hindu cow get slapped
一头印度母牛被一个壮汉狠狠地扇了一巴掌一样。
hard I just got slapped in the face
我刚才也被扇了一巴掌，
that's going to be a huge TV moment
这绝对会成为电视史上一个经典瞬间。这是
award he's to be admired incredible
颁奖典礼，他值得敬佩，真是个了不起的
man you were on stage as well you know a
人。
couple of months after when Dave
几个月后，戴夫·
Chappelle was attacked I actually saw
查普尔遭到袭击时，
you in the back I remember seeing you
你也在台上。我记得当时你在后台，你
sort of come out and just you you kind
走出来，
of looked a little bit like security but
看起来有点像保安，但又
maybe not the most yeah me me well
不太像。嗯，
security
保安。
so when when Dave got rushed uh and it
所以当戴夫被冲过来的时候，情况
was very scary because you know it could
非常可怕，因为你知道，事情可能会朝着
have gone another way um you know the
另一个方向发展。那
guy had a knife orbe it a knife in a gun
个人手里拿着刀，或者说是枪里藏着一把刀，那感觉就像是…… 一把
gun that pressed a button and a knife
枪，按下按钮，一把刀就弹出来了，嗯，是的，是的，
yes it was it was it was a knife that
是一把刀，
identified as a gun maybe I don't know
看起来像枪，也许吧，我不知道。总之，嗯，是的，
anyway so um yeah I remember I was
我记得当时我
standing with Jeff Ross on the side of
和杰夫·罗斯站在
the stage and then and then this this
舞台边上，然后，然后，这
thing happened it was yeah it was it's
事发生了，是的，是的，太疯狂了，太
scary had he got his ass beat the person
可怕了。他被揍了一顿，那个
that ran out and got stomped out by like
跑出来被踩扁的人，嗯，
well he got the reason he got stomped
他被踩扁的原因
out wasn't it wasn't um uh malice it was
不是，不是恶意，而是
he wouldn't let go of the gun knife so
他不肯松开那把枪刀。
the guy had a gun what looked like a gun
那家伙拿着一把看起来像枪的枪，
I mean it was a gun and he wouldn't let
我的意思是，它就是一把枪，他不肯松手。
go of it and they I think um the
我想，
security guys um uh broke his arm
保安人员为了夺下那把枪，打断了他的胳膊。是的，
but what are you going to do let the guy
你能怎么办？让那家伙
have the gun like it's a it's yeah it's
拿着枪吗？这很，是的，
very yeah pretty scary uh scary thing
非常可怕。可怕的事情，
are CH times changing in terms of
时代在改变吗？
violence towards comedians is think so I
针对喜剧演员的暴力事件正在发生改变，我认为是的，我
think they're they're isolated into uh
认为他们…… 他们被隔离了，呃，
Eddie Murphy had the best line on it
埃迪·墨菲对此有一句最精彩的台词。
Eddie Murphy said uh he said Will Smith
埃迪·墨菲说，呃，他说威尔·史密斯打了
when he slapped Chris Rock rang the
克里斯·洛克一巴掌，就像敲响了疯狂的钟，
crazy all the crazies came out for a
所有疯子都出来闹事好
couple couple of weeks the guy rushes um
几个星期。那家伙冲向查
Chappelle it's not it's not a great
普尔，情况不太好，
situation I mean it's like it's it's a
我的意思是，
scary thing when you think you know
当你想到你的
friends getting rushed by someone with a
朋友被一个拿刀的人冲过来时，
knife and you sort of think of what
你会想到
could have happened but he was fine and
可能会发生什么，这很可怕。但他没事，
obviously you know was shaken in the
显然当时受到了惊吓，
moment but he was pretty pretty
但他
philosophical about it anyone ever
对此相当冷静。有人
attacked you on stage no I mean
在舞台上攻击过你吗？没有，我是说
threatened you yeah I've been I've been
威胁过你。是的，我被
threatened a little bit but okay
威胁过一点，但好吧，这
not part of the game I guess I mean it's
不属于游戏的一部分。我的意思是，
like it's that weird thing of like when
这就像那种奇怪的事情，就像
you there's a there's a routine in it I
你有一个固定的环节，我在
canceled on the on the special and you
特别节目里稍微谈到了被取消的事情，然后你
talk about like what I'm going to do
谈到了下次我要做什么，
next time because it's going to happen
因为…… 这事还会再发生，对吧？
again right so the next time I get
所以下次我再被“
canceled I've got a plan here's what I'm
取消”的时候，我已经有了计划。
going to do I'm going to say I've
我会说我已经
rehearsed this I'm going to make a
排练过了，我会在
public statement on the day the news
新闻爆出的当天发表公开声明，说“对不起”。
and the people that are offended will
那些被冒犯的人会
say you don't really mean that apology
说“你根本没真心道歉”，
and I'll say so you're saying I could
我会说“所以你的意思是说我可以
say something and not mean it now you're
说一些话却不是真心的？你现在明白我的意思了，
smart but it's that it's they're jokes
但关键是，这些都是玩笑，
you can't go around apologizing for
你不能到处为
jokes I'm exceptionally excited to sit
玩笑道歉”。我非常期待
down and watch your Netflix special
坐下来观看你的Netflix特辑《
Natural Born Killer which came out on
天生杀手》，它于
April 16th there's been a lot of
4月16日上线。这部特辑引发了很多
conversation around it because I think a
讨论，因为我觉得
lot of people are acknowledging that
很多人都
you've adopted a slightly different
注意到你的
style to the past and everyone's excited
风格和以前略有不同，大家都很兴奋地
to see this this newer Jimmy this
看到这个全新的吉米，这个经过
this heavily iterated optimized version
反复迭代优化、
of Jimmy that's taken 51 years to
耗时51年
produce and I always talk to people
打造的吉米版本。我总是和人们谈论
about our last conversation and you
我们的 上次谈话中，你
telling me that even you at at the peak
告诉我，即使在
of the mountain in many people's eyes
许多人眼中你已经站在了人生的巅峰，你
are still trying to find small marginal
仍然在努力寻找微小的
gains and and challenge yourself and
进步，挑战自我，
come out of your comfort zone and I
走出舒适区。我
think that's exactly what you do in this
认为这正是你在这个
special I've been fortunate enough to
特别节目中所做的。我有幸
see some of the the jokes and the angles
观看了其中的一些笑话和角度，不知
reason it feels to me like Society needs
为何，我觉得社会也需要
to have some of these conversations as
进行一些类似的对话。所以，
well so what even though there is humor
尽管
there underneath the the jokes you tell
你讲的笑话背后有很多幽默，但
there's um I think there's an underlying
我认为其中蕴含着一个
important message that's greeting
重要的信息，
Society at the right
在恰当的
moment I very much appreciate that is
时机向社会传递。我非常欣赏这一点。我的
assessment I think it is I think it's it
评价准确吗？我认为是的。这个
has it is different to the last special
特别节目与上一个有所不同，
and it's got more of me in it and it's
它更多地展现了我的个人风格。
like I'm in a very privileged position
感觉我身处一个非常特殊的位置，
where people you know some people listen
有些人会听
to me uh and I have my audience I know
我的，我有自己的听众，我知道
what my audience are so I can I can get
我的听众是谁，所以我可以及时传递一些
other people can't really talk about and
其他人无法公开谈论的信息。所以，如果……
so that thing of going if I'm doing sex
我正在做
ed I do sex ed in my way and it's very
性教育，我用自己的方式做性教育，这很
funny but it's getting a message across
有趣，但它传递的信息
to young men that I think is very
对年轻男性来说非常
valuable I'm excited to listen
有价值。我很兴奋能听到
specifically about the stuff about
关于
consent very very excited Jimmy we have
同意的内容，真的非常兴奋。吉米，我们
a closing tradition on this podcast
这个播客有个结束的传统，上
where the last guest leaves a question
一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留一个问题，但
for the next guest not knowing who
不知道问题会
they're going to be leaving it for oh
留给谁。哦，好吧，
well I've given this literally no
我完全没想过这个问题，
thought so right okay I don't get to see
所以，好吧，我也看不到这个问题，
it either which is funny people don't
这很有趣，人们不
believe me when I say that but okay
相信我说的话。好吧，是
what's the have I got a question you
什么问题？我有个问题。你有一个
have got a question that's been left for
问题，是别人留给
you the question that's been left for
你的。留给
you is what would you tell your
你的问题是：你会对
20-year-old self that you wish you knew
20岁的自己说些什么，你希望自己当时就知道这些，这些话会对
your life and helped you to avoid
你的人生产生积极的影响，帮助你避免
unnecessary
不必要的
pain I think I would have said enjoy
痛苦？我想我会说，多享受生活，多活在当下。
I think I was worried about the results
我想我当时更关心结果，
and not the process at that age I think
而不是过程。我想
I was worried about what kind of degree
我当时更关心的是
I would get uh and working hard and I
我能拿到什么样的学位，还有努力学习。 我当时应该更
should have been worried about having
担心如何玩得
more
更
fun what's telling you in hindsight that
开心。事后看来，是什么让你觉得那是
that's the important thing you needed to
你当时最需要
hear at that point what was the symptom
听到的？
of not hearing that I think it was I
没听到那句话的症状是什么？我觉得，
uh if you're in Academia and you have
如果你身处学术界，又有
that imposter syndrome and you feel like
那种冒名顶替综合症，感觉自己像个傻瓜，觉得“
oh oh God what's what's I don't belong
天哪，我不属于
here I'm not bright enough I need to
这里，我不够聪明，我需要更
work harder that's valuable in one sense
努力”，这在某种意义上是有价值的，
it makes you kind of work harder but
它会让你更加努力。但
actually you know should have what's
实际上，你知道，
what what's college for it's just for
大学的意义是什么？它只是为了
growing up be in the moment I what do
成长，要活在当下。
you think of
你觉得
University I think University is a
大学怎么样？我觉得大学现在是一种
luxury item now I think the intrinsic
奢侈品。我认为
value of university is less important
大学的内在价值远
than the what it signals about you so I
不如它所代表的意义重要。所以我
think a degree from Cambridge is a Louis
觉得剑桥大学的学位就像一个
Vuitton bag it's a luxury item that says
路易威登包，是一种奢侈品，它表明“
oh I have this um you can just get the
哦，我有这个”。你可以直接拿到
reading list and read the books I'm not
阅读清单，然后读那些书。我不确定
academia's you know I don't know I've
学术界是否……你知道，我不知道，我感觉很
got strong views on Academia because I
强大。 我对学术界的看法是，
was when I went to University it was
我上大学的时候是
free right it was very difficult to get
免费的，对吧？虽然很难
in but it was free and I think we should
考上，但是是免费的。我觉得我们应该
bring that back I think if you're doing
恢复这种免费教育。如果你学的是STEM（科学、技术、工程和数学），
let's say stem right let's say you're
比如说，如果你
studying any stem subject University
学的是任何STEM学科，那么
should be free in the UK and if you get
在英国上大学就应该是免费的。如果你
a stem degree from anywhere else in the
在世界其他地方获得了STEM学位，就
world it should come with um British
应该附赠英国
passport
护照。
attached come spend some time here great
来英国待一段时间吧，这很棒。
it's not a bad
这不是什么坏
policy your kid turns to you one day and
政策。有一天，你的孩子对你说：“
says daddy
爸爸，我
I'm I want to be a
想当
magician what' you say to your kid they
魔术师。”你会怎么回答？
want to be a a a magician or they say
或者，如果他们说：“
that I want to be an NBA player let's do
我想当NBA球员，那就试试
that one what' you say to your kid wait
这个吧。”你会怎么回答？等等，
go back become a magician um uh I I
回去，先去当魔术师。嗯……我
don't know I mean listen it's it's uh I
不知道。我的意思是，听着，我
suppose it's that thing of like follow
想这就像“追逐
your
你的
dreams if they're hiring it's Chris
梦想”一样，如果他们在招聘，那就去吧。这
rocks line isn't it yeah Follow Your
不就是克里斯·洛克的那句台词吗？“追逐你的
Passion if they're hiring if you if if
激情”，如果他们在招聘，如果
you're good at that if you're I don't
你擅长，如果你…… 我不
know if my kid winds up being 7 foot I'd
知道我的孩子最终会不会长到七英尺高，我会很
be surprised but if he is then maybe
惊讶，但如果他真的长到七英尺，也许，也许，
maybe then you know maybe there's a
你知道，也许，也许，这其中会有
maybe there's a future in it but
未来。但是，是的，
the yeah pick something that seems
选择一个你认为现实的事情。
about what you want your son to do uh
你对儿子将来想做什么有偏好吗？嗯，说
honestly because we all have I would
实话，因为我们都有，
have a I would have a bit of a bias I I
我也会有点偏好。我的
mean I don't know I don't know what jobs
意思是，我不知道，我不知道三十年后会是什么工作，对吧？
you you want your kid to be happy and
你希望你的孩子快乐，
maybe maybe to have some sort of uh
也许，也许，培养一些
grounding in critical thinking and
批判性思维能力，
beyond that I know good luck Jimmy thank
除此之外，我明白了。祝你好运，Ji 谢谢
you our first conversation really blew
你，我们的第一次对话真的让
me away and it it taught me something
我大吃一惊，它教会了我很多
about actually about this podcast you're
关于这个播客的事情。你是我经历过的最
one of the real defining conversations I
重要的对话之一，它让
had that taught me that
我明白
everyone is much more
每个人都远不止
than the surface that you see and it's
表面看起来那么简单。说起来也挺有意思的，
funny cuz when last time when we
上次我们
recorded it was upstairs in my kitchen
录音的时候是在我家楼上的厨房，就是
my previous kitchen and the team text me
以前的厨房。
when you arrived and they said oh Jimmy
你到了之后，团队给我发短信说：“哦，吉米·
car's just arrived I think you arrived
卡刚到，我想你是骑
on your bicycle or something and they're
自行车来的吧？”他们说：“
like oh God he's just act a joke about
哦，天哪，他刚才还在
someone's mom downstairs and I thought
楼下拿别人的妈妈开玩笑呢。”我当时想：“
oh this is this is Jimmy car the Jimmy
哦，这就是吉米·卡，就是
car I've seen on nine out of 10 cats and
我在《九只猫》里见过的那个吉米·卡。”
then we went upstairs and had that
然后我们就上楼
conversation and it just blew my mind it
聊了起来，那次谈话真的让我大开眼界，真的让我大吃一惊。嗯，
just absolutely blew my mind well this
这
is the difficult second album how did I
是第二张专辑，我
do oh fantastic oh great fantastic
做得怎么样？哦，太棒了！哦，太好了！真的太棒了！
absolutely but no it really it taught me
不过，这次谈话真的让我明白，
that um people are much more than than
人远不止
just the the mask that we wear and we
我们戴的面具那么简单。我们都
all wear a mask you know Persona to get
戴着面具，你知道，人格面具，为了
through life and we find it easier
更好地生活，有时候我们觉得这样更容易些。
sometimes to wear the mask than to
戴上面具比
confront who we actually are but in that
面对真实的自己更轻松，但在那次
ation I feel like I got to meet The Man
经历中，我感觉自己真正见到了
Behind the Mask per se and I I really
面具背后的那个人，我真的很
like sharing that side of myself I I I
喜欢分享我这一面，我真的很
really enjoy this I really enjoy the
喜欢这个
show I wish you every success thank you
节目，祝你一切顺利，
so much Jimmy thank you for everything
非常感谢你，吉米，谢谢你所做的一切，
and I highly recommend everybody go and
我强烈推荐大家去看《
see Natural Born Killer which is on
天生杀人狂》，它
Netflix right now I'm going to put the
现在在Netflix上，我会
link to the Netflix special in the
在下面的描述里放上Netflix特辑的链接。
[Music]
[音乐]
a
a